<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SouthAmerica2011 | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/categories/southamerica2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-01T15:22:55-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://reputablejournal.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iguazu Falls Postscript]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/24/iguazu-falls-postscript/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/24/iguazu-falls-postscript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow,  We were just here and just on this very same boat ride.  I wrote about it here:  <a href="http://blog.bonelakesoftware.com/2011/02/hiking-in-iguazu-national-park.html">http://blog.bonelakesoftware.com/2011/02/hiking-in-iguazu-national-park.html</a>.  Now today I find out that two American tourists have died doing that same excursion.</p>


<p>Apparently the boat hit some rocks and flipped over.  With the power of the falls and that river its amazing that only two people died.  <a href="http://www.smh.com.au/travel/tourists-killed-as-raft-flips-under-iguazu-falls-20110322-1c4f9.html?from=smh_sb">http://www.smh.com.au/travel/tourists-killed-as-raft-flips-under-iguazu-falls-20110322-1c4f9.html?from=smh_sb</a> Its worth following the link to the article as it has an awesome picture of a rescue working being lowered from a helicopter that gives you a sense of the scale of these falls.</p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-3992925394284503538?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruise Wrapup Part II]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/15/cruise-wrapup-part-ii/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/15/cruise-wrapup-part-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been back in Decorah for less than 24 hours, its been a little more than 48 hours since we got off the cruise ship in Valparaiso.  It was great to get a good nights sleep last night after having an overnight flight from Santiago to Dallas.  Boy do I wish I could sleep on airplanes.</p>


<p>The Celebrity debarkation process was about as painless as you could make it. We woke up, showered and dressed, got some coffee at the Cova Cafe, checked our email one last time, and then walked off the ship.  Like Buenos Aires, the port in Valparaiso is not really designed for cruise ships, so we got off the ship and then took a bus through the containers to the actual terminal.   We found our luggage right away and realized that this process was so efficient we still had about 45 minutes to wait before our guide, Mac, from <a href="http://www.labicicletaverde.com/">La Bicicleta Verde</a> It was a little odd this morning because Chile was supposed to go off daylight savings time at the same time the US was supposed to go on daylight savings.  So, in one day we would go from being 3 hours ahead of home to just one hour.  Strangely the government of chile decided at the last minute not to go off daylight savings time, so some people were really off.  Mac showed up just after 9:00, and we got our tour underway.  We started by exploring the hills of Valparaiso.  Its an old shipping town, started when Nitrates were a big natural commodity that was shipped out of here.  Before the Canal, and before artificial nitrates had been invented.  So there are many beautiful old shipping houses owned by the british that have been converted into small hotels.  Here you can see one last view of our ship from the hills:</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2559.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-lgbWQR_I/AAAAAAAAAPs/qYK_mU8OK4g/IMG_2559.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2559" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>We continued on past the first Lutheran Church in Valparaiso, and then had to avoid a pack of street dogs.  All chilean cities are full of street animals that are well feed and mostly well behaved.  The problem this morning was there was one female in heat and four males that were trying to get her attention.  Things got a little violent, so we headed off in the opposite direction hoping to lose the pack.</p>


<p>Mac told us that the day before this whole area of the city had been without power.  Now as you can see from this picture Valparaiso has a very modern system of electrical distribution:</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2566.jpg" src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-lhdhCiAI/AAAAAAAAAPw/T80lkZzXk3c/IMG_2566.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2566" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>We were told that whenever there is a power loss, rather than trying to untangle the mass of wires and fix the problem, they simply find an area of the city that has power and then run a new wire to the blacked out area from there.</p>


<p>After the hill tour we headed down the coastline to visit some of the beautiful coastal towns, suchas Vina del Mar.  This would be an awesome place to come back and visit on a land tour.  The beaches are spectacular, and there are some really awesome restaurants looking right out over the water.  Mac got us number one at the most popular restaurant along this stretch.  People literally line up outside this restaurant waiting for a table.  Something that is unheard of in Chile.  We started off with a couple of apetizers:  Machas ala parmesan (razor clams smothered in a parmesan cream sauce.)  The only way to sum up this dish is:  To Die For!  We also had Camerones pil pil (little shrimp scampi).  Then for the main course we had freshly prepared fish.  They have about 7 different kinds of fish on the menu, each one with several different preparations.  I had Albacora (swordfish) grilled, and Jane had the Corvina (chilean sea bass) also grilled.  We had a side of Arroz and thought we were in heaven.  What a great last meal of the trip.  Oh, lest I forget , I also had my first Pisco Sour.  Pisco Sour is a great chilean drink made of a distilled wine (kind of like brandy) served with lime juice and simple syrup.  Just one please!</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2569.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-liHkJ7eI/AAAAAAAAAP0/PeTTyYLJ17E/IMG_2569.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2569" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>After our delicious lunch we headed out to wine country.  The Casablanca valley is between Valparaiso and Santiago.  We stopped at the Emiliana Organic Vineyards, for a wine tasting and a walk around the vineyards.  We had a great wine steward, named Joshua, who served us samples of their premium Emiliana Adobe line.  This is sold in the United States under the Emiliana Natura label because of  a trademark dispute with the Adobe software company.  Please lawyers find something more productive to do with your time.  The highlight was their Gewurtztraminer, its not nearly as sweet as the German Gewurtztraminers and was very refreshing.  In addition to being organic they also practice Biodynamics (you'll have to look it up).  This sounds like a lot of hokum to me, but you can't argue with the results.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2574.jpg" src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-ljPq7YOI/AAAAAAAAAP4/6L6V9pT56Iw/IMG_2574.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2574" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>Finally, what trip would be complete without some cute animals.  The vineyard also raises Alpacas, which we learned are part of the Camel family.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2585.jpg" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-lj20NJvI/AAAAAAAAAP8/DyB6X7faf6c/IMG_2585.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2585" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>With the vineyard tour over, our last stop was the Santiago airport.  We had lots of time to kill, since we got there about 5pm and our flight wasn't supposed to leave until 10:05.  Of course at 5:00 the American Airlines counters were not even open yet. Then at 6:00 when they opened it was a mad house.  hundreds of tired cruisers all anxious to get home, and all accustomed to being pampered for two weeks were now forced to stand in extremely long lines like so many commoners.  It was not pretty.  An interesting thing about flying out of Santiago is that all the outgoing flights leave in the evening, this is partly because you want to time your flight to get in to the states at a decent hour of the morning.  Say 6:00 AM or so.  But all the incoming flights get in to Santiago at 7 or 8 in the morning anyway, so why not have an outbound flight at 10AM?  By Chilean law, all outbound flights must have a complete mechanical inspection within 12 hours of their flight by a Chilean mechanical team.  The reason for this law dates back to 1972 when the Uruguayan rugby team crashed in the Andes and resorted to cannibalism to stay alive.  The Chilean legislature wanted to ensure that nothing like this would ever happen again so they passed this inspection law.  The result is that the flights that leave in the evening are never delayed for mechanical reasons, because they've had all day to inspect and fix everything.  Nice, makes you feel safe.</p>


<p>Well, that brings us as far as our last flights, which were pretty uneventful.  A bit of turbulence somewhere between Santiago and Dallas is about the only thing worth mentioning.  This was an awesome trip.  Thanks again to all the great new friends we made on board the ship for making it a fun time!</p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-570044920896128868?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruise Wrapup Part I]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/15/cruise-wrapup-part-i/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/15/cruise-wrapup-part-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its the last day aboard ship, and it has been a day of mixed emotions.  We are excited to get back to our friends and family in Decorah, yet we have had so much fun on this cruise, and we have actually met some great people as well.  Some of these people get to stay on the ship for the next leg of the cruise and as we think about our long day tomorrow and our overnight flight we are a bit jealous that we don&rsquo;t get to go through the Panama canal, and then fly home from Fort Lauderdale.  I&rsquo;m amazed that I could even consider staying onboard for another two weeks, but we&rsquo;ve learned that its really all about pacing (note to self, next time do not buy the unlimited drinks package.)<br /><br />The cruise critic message boards really provide a great service.  Not only can you find good reviews and recommendations of the non-ship excursions, but we&rsquo;ve met a lot of fun people, and have been able to enjoy excursions with people that we met online prior to the cruise. So to Carol and Mike, and Carol and Ralph, and Scott and Gai, and Kristine and Craig (our aussie friends)&hellip; Thanks!!  To Jonathan and Nancy and Jo, we look forward to the final Martini rankings, Aloha!  And to Shila and Yogi, Kim and Rico, Rachel and Howie, thanks again for the fun dinners!  Hopefully we&rsquo;ll cross paths with some of you again on a future cruise.<br /><br />So, where have we been?  Here&rsquo;s the super-fast summary of our travels:<br /><br />Decorah to MSP with Jenkins, Thanks for the ride guys!<br /><br />MSP to Dallas<br /><br />Dallas to EZE (Buenos Aires)  cross town transfer to Jorge Newberry and then on to Iguazu<br /><br />Two fantastic days at Iguazu falls.  If you are looking at this cruise or planning a trip to South America, do not skip Iguazu.  The views are fantastic.<br /><br />Iguazu back to BA and on to the ship!<br /><br />BA to Montevideo, Uruguay<br /><br />Montevideo to Punta del Este<br /><br />Punta del Este to Puerto Madryn &mdash; Desert like climate but great penguins and sea lions.<br /><br />Puerto Madryn to Cape Horn and the Ushuaia (Ushuaia gets my vote for favorite city of the trip)  Its the southernmost city of the world, and the hiking and views on our hike in Tierra del Fuego national park were just phenomenal!<br /><br />Ushuaia to Punta Arenas&hellip; OK, but not that spectacular.  If you haven&rsquo;t seen penguins by now, you should definitely do the trip here to see the penguins.<br /><br />Punta Arenas to Puerto Montt.  The port area is not spectacular, but once you get out into the country or to one of the other smaller neighboring cities its great.  Beautiful scenery&hellip;. second favorite city.  Of course the zip line ride really made this stop worthwhile.<br /><br />Puerto Montt to Valparaiso to Santiago<br /><br />Santiago to Dallas<br /><br />Dallas to MSP<br /><br />Ride home with Sandy Larsen!  Wow gone 16 days and no parking charges at the airport!<br /><br />Other stuff:<br /><br />While on board, we used up 435 minutes of internet time.<br /><br />We drank 2 bottles of wine :&ndash;)  or more&hellip;<br /><br />Jane won $700 at the craps table<br /><br />We really enjoyed many of the shows onboard the Celebrity Infinity!  We had become pretty much jaded about cruise line entertainment, but the quality here was really high.  I missed having a magic show, but the music was mostly really great, except for the aging former Argentine star, who just doesn&rsquo;t realize its time to hang it up.  When you are on a cruise ship and you have to start your show with a video about how great you used to be, that is not a good sign!  Travis, from Nebraska, you rock.  The a cappella group top shelf was great too.  It was hard to listen to this recently graduated group of young guys without thinking about Kaia&rsquo;s future as a musical performer.<br /><br />No summary would be complete without some room pictures, so here are a few pics of our Celebrity Suite.  This suite will be redone when the ship is Solticized in November, but we thought it was perfect for this cruise.  Not only was the room spectacular, but our Butler, Teguh, was the most Amazing person.  No job was too big or too small, he really made our cruise seamless.  From sneaking into the room before I was awake every morning so that my coffee was hot and fresh on the table, to organizing a part for 20 in our room one night.  He was the best!<br /><br /><img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-PJOMhXDI/AAAAAAAAAPY/PsUFK601Bv8/IMG_2543.jpg?imgmax=800" alt="IMG 2543" title="IMG_2543.jpg" border="0" width="400" height="266" /><img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-PJpXrJJI/AAAAAAAAAPc/kB9mgIbKAyQ/IMG_2546.jpg?imgmax=800" alt="IMG 2546" title="IMG_2546.jpg" border="0" width="400" height="266" /><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-PK0iEIUI/AAAAAAAAAPk/kZFodvDVsJ0/IMG_2556.jpg?imgmax=800" alt="IMG 2556" title="IMG_2556.jpg" border="0" width="400" height="266" /><img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TX-PKMDxmxI/AAAAAAAAAPg/H6iOyzx5yqw/IMG_2549.jpg?imgmax=800" alt="IMG 2549" title="IMG_2549.jpg" border="0" width="400" height="266" /><br /><br />Jane says I can type and read at the airport tomorrow, so I think its time to get dressed for dinner one last time!<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-2808293707145995482?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tsunami Warning!]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/11/tsunami-warning/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/11/tsunami-warning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is weird, but I woke up this morning wondering about the question:  "what are the ships procedures in case of a Tsunami?"  Would we head for the open sea and ride out the giant fast moving swell there, or would we seek safe haven in a harbor of some kind.  Then, when Jane checked her email and the news she told me about the 8.9 magnitude earthquake in Japan, and the Tsunami warning issued for the entire Pacific Ocean.  I didn't really give it much thought, because after all we are a LONG way away from Japan.  However, when we were in the tour bus this morning, our guide told us that they were evacuating Easter Island and some of the other Chilean Islands.  OK, maybe this is more serious than we thought.  Now I was thinking what kind of damage could be done to the harbor in Valparaiso?  Will the tsunami have an impact on our trip home?  When we returned from touring we noticed that they were essentially evacuating the harbor, all of the ships we already towed out or in the process of being moved out of the harbor to more open water.  Score one for the open water solution.</p>


<p>As far as we know, this is not going to have a big impact on our trip. Out at sea, the tsunami is nothing but a big swell that we would ride up and over like any other large swell.  Its only when it gets toward land that it becomes the giant wall of water you see on the news. The captain is going about business as usual and we are on our way out of the harbor at Puerto Montt as I write this.  We have about 650 nautical miles from here to Valparaiso, and tomorrow we will spend a relaxing last day at sea.  If we were the tsunami, we would be able to get there in just a little over an hour!  According to news reports the wave traveled from japan toward Hawaii and the west coast of the US at over 500 mph.  The pictures of Japan on the news are just unbelievable, but again it appears that distance will sufficiently weaken the tsunami to the point where we will not be affected at all.</p>


<p>So, lets turn our attention to our fabulous day here in Puerto Montt!  We got to check off a bucket list item today.  What could that be you ask?   Zip Lining!  The highlight of todays tour was going to the top of a volcano, and then riding a series of zip lines to the bottom.  When we arrived on the pier this morning it was quite overcast and the owner of the tour company warned us that with the rain from last night and the wind today we might be out of luck.  But we took off in our little bus and headed for Lago Llanguihue, this is a huge vacation lake that sits below the volcanoes.  And when we arrived at the base of the ski lift on the volcano it appeared that we might in fact be out of luck.  Here's a view of what the side of the volcano/ski area looked like:</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2473.jpg" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXqX0iHLHrI/AAAAAAAAAO8/JMf5VBQolOI/IMG_2473.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2473" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>We were clearly in and above the cloud line, and it was really eerie to see the wisps of clouds, that looked like steam rising from the dark sides of the volcano.  Our guide told us that we would not be allowed to go because of the wind.  So, we just hung out for a while looking at the clouds and suddenly we noticed that the sky towards the top was starting to clear.  Suddenly the chair lift even started running.  Our guide came out and said OK team lets head down and we'll go into Puerto Vargassafsf for some shopping and a nice lunch.  Wait!  a couple of the women (including jane) said.  Can't we at least ride up the chair lift?  Of course I'm thinking you guys are mad, why would we want to ride higher up into the clouds to just see more clouds.  So our guide told us to wait and she would check.  Miraculously, now the 'experts' were out checking the zip lines to see if they were safe.  The verdict came back that it was safe, so a few of us decided to follow the original plan and go for it.</p>


<p>When we reached the top of the ski lift we were treated to the following view:</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2496.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXqX8LWOwjI/AAAAAAAAAPA/Zuh96Wv5Jtc/IMG_2496.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2496" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>Clearly you can see the clouds had dissipated and we had a fantastic view of the top of the volcano, and its glacier.  It took us a few minutes, as the guy working at the top of the lift did not speak any english, but we eventually located our zip lining guides.  They got us into our harnesses and led us to the top of the launching pad for our very brief (10 seconds?) safety briefing.</p>


<p>Him:   hold</p>


<p>Me:  Si</p>


<p>Him:  break</p>


<p>Me: Si</p>


<p>Him:  No touch the cable, only here and the break</p>


<p>Me:  Si</p>


<p>And off you go!</p>


<p>Here's Jane and our friend Scott before we got our helmets.  Those harnesses are certainly stylish.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2484.jpg" src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXqYAyClIJI/AAAAAAAAAPE/8oIy5boEdg4/IMG_2484.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2484" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>And now here's Jane on her first run of the day.  Yes kids thats your mother hanging by a thread from a long thin piece of cable..  Don't worry she's having the time of her life.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2486.jpg" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXqYEx22OBI/AAAAAAAAAPI/3vNQbo2GBJc/IMG_2486.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2486" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p> </p>


<p>And now here's one of me coming in for a landing after our longest ride.  The span of this ride was 600 meters!  The total ride time was about 38 seconds which means our average speed was 15.78 meters/second or about 35 mph.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2519.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXqYOBwCnPI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/g945yXZ8Cis/IMG_2519.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2519" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>In all, we got to go on four different runs, each was great and very exhilarating.  We had an adrenaline rush for a good hour after we were all done, talking excitedly in the bus all the way back down the volcano.  A great day and a lot of fun.  Can't wait to try it again sometime!</p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-4524677153241371099?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the High Seas]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/10/on-the-high-seas/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2011/03/10/on-the-high-seas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are sitting here having our morning coffee and hot chocolate watching the waves crash and roll.  We left the Straits of Magellan sometime in the middle of the night and entered the Pacific Ocean, where we have high winds and, as the captain says, "Big Waves."  I took some video looking out our window, but I'm not sure you can get the real sense of how much we are rocking and rolling.  I'll post the video when we have a faster internet connection.  Meanwhile I just walked down the stairs to the Cova Cafe to get some of their great little croissants for breakfast, and I noticed that the crew has strategically placed barf bags along the stairwells and in other places.  According to the captain, who just updated us, we are experiencing winds at 50-60 knots with gusts of 70 knots.  In addition the waves are 15-20 feet high.</p>


<p>I just got back from the workout room.  walking up the stairs was quite an adventure.  At times I felt like I was floating up two to three stairs at a time, and at other times, I felt like I was carrying an elephant on my back as I was trying to go up a single stair.  Bootcamp was postponed this morning due to the high seas.  I decided to go ahead on run on the elliptical, which was kind of fun with all the dipping and plunging the ship was doing.</p>


<p>We will be at sea today, and tomorrow, although later today and all of tomorrow we will be cruising through the Chilean Fjords. The Fjords will be much calmer than the open ocean.  I'm not sure whether or not to even attempt to go to bootcamp workout in these high waves.</p>


<p>Yesterday we were in Punta Arenas.  It was our first stop in Chile.  We did not do any kind of excursion or tour.  We just took the tender to shore and walked around the town a bit.  There was a nice park square with trees, and a statue of Magellan, and handicrafts.  Apparently you are supposed to kiss the toe of Magellan and you will come back again, but with the crew having you sanitize your hands every five minutes, I can't imagine why anyone would want to kiss the toe of a statue and share the germs of a hundred other travelers that way!</p>


<p>While we were in town we found an internet cafe, where for the price of a cup of coffee we could get all the free internet we wanted.  It was nice to have some high speed internet for a change.</p>


<p>We just got back from a tour of the bridge.  It was very interesting and one of the officers confirmed that the wind was very strong this morning.  He said the maximum gust was 99 knots.  Thats about 113 mph for you non-nautical types.  So what do you do when you have a twelve story floating building and the wind is blowing against one side of the building at 113 mph?  Several things, it turns out.  The ship has stabilizers that can be deployed to counteract the forces of the wind.  These protrude out of the ship under the water at an angle like long wings that are under the water.  In addition there is water ballast that can be pumped from one side of the ship to the other to counteract the wind and the seas.  So when you consider that we had a strong current, 15 foot waves, and strong winds gusting to over 100 mph its amazing how little rocking and rolling the ship actually did.</p>


<p>Here are a couple of photos I snapped while we were on the bridge:</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2431.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXjbh0HJ9qI/AAAAAAAAAOs/pkGU1w4_I9k/IMG_2431.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2431" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p> </p>


<p><img title="IMG_2434.jpg" src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXjbk6YrraI/AAAAAAAAAOw/xwMnty7DU9U/IMG_2434.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2434" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p>Since we are back we are also getting ready to host a little party in our room for some of the people we've met on board.  The party will start here, and then we'll also visit some of the rooms and suites that others have.  This is a great way to see what kind of room you might like to have the next time you come on board.  Here's a shot that I took on the balcony of our friends Jonathan and Nancy.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2449.jpg" src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TXjbnlgognI/AAAAAAAAAO0/mgpnUub8tdg/IMG_2449.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG 2449" width="400" height="266" /></p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-1207236459462121750?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
