<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-19T09:29:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JTerm 2014 - Day 1 at Amazon]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T17:08:03-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jeff Bezos likes to talk about technology and civilization and where we are at in terms of the analogy that we are still at &ldquo;Day One.&rdquo;  He recently observed that we are so early in Day One that the alarm clock hasn&rsquo;t even gone off yet.</p>

<blockquote><p>With new technologies, it’s very tempting to think that you’re further along than you are. But usually, you’re more primitive than you think. My guess is we’re still pretty primitive. We as a society, as a civilization. I doubt we have figured out the new technologies very well yet. At Amazon, we’re doing our part in trying to push things forward, but I have the feeling it’s Day One.</p></blockquote>

<p>And so it was that we found ourselves in the building called Day One South, meeting with our very gracious host Sam. This was a great way to start, and although Sam had not been prompted in any way about what to say, he hit on some of key themes for the students to take away from the course:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Passion</strong> &mdash; You are going to work long hours, so you want to find a place to work and a job to do at that place where you are passionate about whatever it is.  If you aren&rsquo;t excited about it, keep looking.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Culture</strong> &mdash; This part of the discussion brought back both great memories and ulcers in my stomach from the days when Amazon was a Net Perceptions customer.  I&rsquo;ve never been pushed harder than I was by Jennifer Jacobi (JJ) when she was my primary contact at Amazon.  She challenged us, held our feet to the fire, threatened to dump us, and ultimately helped us create a better product.  Apparently this is how Amazon treats all its suppliers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Risk</strong> &mdash; High tech companies are full of risk takers.  Sam was no exception as a young graduate who simply moved to Seattle in search of a job.  Years later he is still at Amazon.  Many more years later than he expected.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/Amazon.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After our meeting with Amazon we found a coffee shop where we could take over a large table and had some group discussion.  I told my own story of Net Perceptions, which I should probably write down here soon, and tried to relate my own experience with the themes I want the students to look for over the next three weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Envisioning the Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/envisioning-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T12:38:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/envisioning-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a big day.  The Microsoft mother ship.</p>

<p>We began our visit with an hour in the Envisioning Center, this is Microsoft&rsquo;s take on the future, 5 years out.  There was some pretty cool stuff in there.  If you&rsquo;ve ever drooled over the fancy table on Hawaii Five-O where they can flick things from phone to table, table to screen, etc. You have a pretty good idea of where Microsoft thinks the workplace of the future is headed.  I&rsquo;m there, I want it.  I&rsquo;m already imagining myself walking into the classroom, iPad in hand, and flicking a copy of where we left off last class from my iPad to the board.  Wait, thats a bit of a mixed vision, I&rsquo;m pretty sure they were surface pads, not iPads.  But you get the idea.</p>

<p>After the Envisioning center we moved to another of the 128 buildings on the Microsoft campus where we had time to have our daily group meeting and book presentation.  We were escorted by Tina Wang, and she joined in to the discussion of Sara Lacy&rsquo;s Once you&rsquo;re Lucky, Twice you&rsquo;re good.  Tina works as part of Enwe&rsquo;s group, but is the only one here in the US.  After our lunch we had a really fun talk with Neil Leslie, who shared a lot of wisdom with the group.  And finally Dave Maltz joined us for a final hour on scaling up the data center.  Its fair to say that by the time Dave was done everyone had soaked up about as much information as is possible for brain to take in one day.</p>

<p>A couple observations.  This is not the Microsoft of the 90&rsquo;s.  The Microsoft that I knew and worked with at Net Perceptions were, well, to be blunt, they were bullies back then, because they could be.  I get a real sense that is gone.  Instead they talk of change, how they need to compete, and if you&rsquo;re comfortable, you shouldn&rsquo;t be there.</p>

<p>Returning to key themes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Passion:  I don&rsquo;t think I need to say more about this.</li>
<li>Projects:  I&rsquo;ve told my seniors this for a few years now, but it has a lot more credibility coming from an outsider.  You need to have a project to show when you go to interview.  Bring an app you have built on your phone.  Show a website you have developed on the browser.  Be prepared to talk about the challenges, trade-offs, and succeesses you have had in developing your project.</li>
<li>Linked In:  This is a critical tool for finding a job.  If you are a CS junior or senior and have not created a LinkedIn profile.  Do it now.</li>
<li>Failure:  We heard a lot of stories about failure today, and we will continue to hear of them.  Startups, started and &lsquo;buried,&rsquo; products and projects that failed and never saw the light of day.  The most important message, that I hope students get from this trip, and talking to a bunch of successful people, is that failure is OK.  <strong>Fail Fast</strong>, and learn from your mistakes.  It is a cliche to say that you learn more from failure than success, but it is true.</li>
</ul>


<p>In the evening it was fun to unwind with our first group dinner.  We met up with recent Luther Alum Jake Nowosatka at Cutters Crabhouse.  Its at the far end of Pike Place Market.</p>

<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/PikePlace.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And Now It Can Be Told]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loyal readers will remember that last summer we cruised to Alaska, and some very secretive things were happening on that cruise that I could only refer to rather cryptically.  Well, with the airing of last nights episode of Top Chef the story can now be told.</p>




<p><p>We were on the set for the filming of the Quickfire challenge onboard the ship!  Although the filming took several hours, we got less than 1 second of screen time.  But here we are!  Brian and I happened to be in a pretty good spot as the camera flashes past us several times.  The ladies we were talking to turned out to be from Wisconsin, in fact from right by our cabin!  The two in the print shirts actually got an additional 2 seconds of screen time along with their comments on the food.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8433342727" title="View 'IMG_0276' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0276" alt="IMG_0276" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8354/8433342727_68204d7fdd.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>Jane, Brian, and I all made it on again towards the end of the challenge.  Sadly there is no sign of Holly.
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8434428742" title="View 'IMG_0277' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0277" alt="IMG_0277" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8355/8434428742_32af448c8b.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p><p>Of course since this was all way before the show started we had no idea who any of the chefs really were.  I do remember really liking Sheldon&rsquo;s lettuce cups as well as Stefan&rsquo;s little potato soup cup.  I could swear that I remember seeing Kristin on the ship, so maybe she got to come along since she would be competing in last chance kitchen in Juneau. </p></p>

<p><p>Right now I&rsquo;m looking forward to the finale.  I&rsquo;m not sure who I want to win the most, with Stefan and Josie gone all the villains are off the show.  I think it would be awesome if Kristin makes it through LCK and gets to compete against Sheldon or Josh in the Finale.  Thats Josh, by the way, in the first photo.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The DeBary Institute]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/25/the-debary-institute/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/25/the-debary-institute</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its been a great J-Term.  A trip to Vail for some Skiing, <strong>and</strong> a trip to Florida to solve the worlds problems with great friends at the DeBary Institute.  For those who do not know, the DeBary institute is a newly renowned think tank with roots in the Bone Lake Global Institute.</p>

<p>We arrived on Friday and spent a wonderful late afternoon enjoying the hospitality and home of our host, Tim Peter.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8405885066" title="View 'IMG_0214' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0214" alt="IMG_0214" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8510/8405885066_aaa4dd8469.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>On Saturday we toured Stetson University in the morning.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8405885966" title="View 'IMG_0221' on Flickr.com"><img height="500" title="IMG_0221" alt="IMG_0221" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8212/8405885966_564e8ca398.jpg" width="375"/></a></p>

<p>Later we repaired to Smyrna Beach, it was a bit windy but we enjoyed it all the same.
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8404793959" title="View 'IMG_0229' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0229" alt="IMG_0229" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8237/8404793959_3faa6ba998.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>The culinary highlight of our trip was dinner at the Swamp House Grill and Tiki Bar.  We enjoyed some lovely alligator bites as appetizers:
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8405887432" title="View 'IMG_0236' on Flickr.com"><img height="200" title="IMG_0236" alt="IMG_0236" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8374/8405887432_1b8fb2bf27.jpg" /></a>  (Yes, as the famous frog said, they do taste like chicken)</p>

<p>After dinner we sat around enjoying the music of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/markdmooreoriginals">Mark Moore</a>.</p>

<p>Sunday was Football (European and American) and then Golf day.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8405887790" title="View 'IMG_0245' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0245" alt="IMG_0245" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8516/8405887790_1e84e19b80.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>Dinner was provided by Gregory and Brad who made a charming seafood alfredo.</p>

<p>Monday morning we left the house at 5:50AM.   The temperature was 62 degrees.  Five hours later we arrived in Cedar Rapids where the temperature was -2.  Thats a big swing for a monday morning.</p>

<p>Already looking forward to next year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vail 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/vail-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/vail-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just got back from four awesome days of skiing in Vail and Beaver Creek.</p>


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8370576743" title="View 'Vail 2013' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="Vail 2013" alt="Vail 2013" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8079/8370576743_c4f2dc7325.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>The Colorado resorts have a really cool new way of handling the ski passes, instead of clipping a tag on your jacket you now get a credit card with an RFID chip in it.  Talk about a ski pass that appeals to the Geek in me!  But whats even better is that every time you go on a lift, there is an RFID reader that grabs your ID and logs that lift ride.  So now at the end of the day you can go on to a website and see how many vertical feet you skiied that day.  Very cool.  Over our four days of skiing we did just over 95,000 vertical feet!  If we'd only known how close to 100k we would get we surely would have had a shorter lunch break on day one!</p>


<p>Since snow started late and has been a bit sparse since Christmas there was a lot of snow making going on.  The mounds of snow created by the snow machines remind you of a Dr. Seuss drawing:

<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8370575981" title="View 'Vail 2013' on Flickr.com"><img height="241" title="Vail 2013" alt="Vail 2013" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8367/8370575981_cdf794cd8c.jpg" width="500"/></a>
</p>




<p>I'm pleased to say that my skiing has really improved thanks to my Solomon BBR 8.9 skis.  I've started to call them my magic skis because I can even do the moguls!  Here's a picture I took of craig at the top of one particularly narrow and moguly run.  Note that I got down first with enough time to turn around and snap some pictures.

<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8371644502" title="View 'Vail 2013' on Flickr.com"><img height="500" title="Vail 2013" alt="Vail 2013" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8190/8371644502_c6ea8baee7.jpg" width="375"/></a></p>




<p>Here's another shot of Craig just before he jumped off the cliff.  Note once again who went first to take the picture:   :-)
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8370575729" title="View 'Vail 2013' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="Vail 2013" alt="Vail 2013" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8470/8370575729_b21214285b.jpg" width="500"/></a> </p>




<p>All in all it was a great four days of skiing with the guys.  Can't wait until next year. </p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
