<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-01T08:35:15-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://reputablejournal.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Visits]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/25/final-visits/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T17:29:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/25/final-visits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My daughter Kaia is getting married next summer.  This is not new news, the proposal was made an accepted last June.  But planning is in full swing now, and I was kind of excited when secured a visit with Capsule, because capsule provides a service where all the guests at your wedding can download the capsule app and it will automatically upload all the photos to a special page for the wedding.</p>

<p>This company was founded by Cyrus, who set out to solve a simple problem, a problem we&rsquo;ve been coping with on this course as well.  When you travel, how do you share all your digital photos with the buddies you are traveling with.  When you have a big party?  When you have a wedding, bachelor party, bachelorette party?  Capsule has solved this in a nice, elegant way.  All the photos uploaded for a particular event, are shared with the participants in the event.  Its that easy.  No need to bore all of your Facebook followers with every photo from your trip.  If you&rsquo;re an Instagram user, its super easy to add a special hashtag to your photo and it will be automatically imported into Capsule as well as shared on Instagram.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>What was incredibly interesting for me was to listen to Cyrus talk about business models, and monetizing the service.  Cyrus is not a CS guy, he&rsquo;s a business guy.  Of course as an entrepreneur he can talk the tech talk but his home is on the business side.  Here&rsquo;s an example of how differently we tech people approach a problem than the business guys.</p>

<p><strong>Problem:</strong> Each event needs to have a unique id, that can be given to the participants to use to join the event, and/or tag their Instagram photos.</p>

<p><strong>Tech Solution:</strong> Ha, this is easy, we&rsquo;ll just allow people to pick a unique identifier, lets say <code>#TannerAndKaia</code> No problem, this is easy just give them a text entry box, and a quick database lookup to make sure the hashtag hasn&rsquo;t already been taken.  No big deal, even an intern could code this up.</p>

<p><strong>Business Guy Solution:</strong>  Ok, just generate a random hashtag <code>#JK286TJ</code>.  Now if the bride and the groom want to have a nice hashtag for their wedding, we can sell them that as a strategy to monetize the service.</p>

<p>Brilliant!  We tech guys get so focused on the solution most of the time that we never stop to think about simple strategies to monetize.</p>

<p>Our second visit of the day was to <a href="http://fullscreen.net" title="Fullscreen">Fullscreen</a>.  This is a Culver City company that employs three Luther Alumni!  Two of which I am very proud to say are also alumni of this very course.  Drew is employee number 3 of Fullscreen, and Aaron is number 15, Jacob is not far after Aaron.  Fullscreen now numbers over 220 employees, and is a very fast growing new media company.</p>

<p>What do they do?  What do you mean new media company?  Well, this is where my age really starts to show.  Apparently there are people in this world that spend a lot of time watching &ldquo;shows&rdquo; on youTube.  Shows like that <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/JennaMarbles" title="JennaMarbles">Marbles girl</a>, or teenagegirl14, and thousands of others.  As Aaron said, this is not your demographic Brad, this is targeted at a group of people that will probably never pay a cable bill.  So Fullscreen is a Network in the sense that they aggregate all kinds of these new generation entertainers, and help them monetize their videos on youtube.  Note that monetize is a euphemism for ad serving, but thats really only a small part of what Fullscreen is about.  Its a great company and Drew, Aaron, and Jacob were excellent hosts.  They even talked their CEO into spending about an hour with us answering questions.</p>

<p>Another interesting story around Fullscreen is that Drew and George (CEO of Fullscreen) met at Coloft Santa Monica.  We were also lucky enough to meet with the founder of Coloft, Avesta, (@avestar). He gave the students  a great no-nonsense talk on his views of entrepreneurship. The story of Drew meeting George is a great example of the synergies that can happen in a co-working facility.  At the time, Drew and a partner were trying to start a little consulting company to do coding for hire.  Avesta happened to be talking to George who was looking for someone with Drew&rsquo;s skill set.  So he introduced the two of them, and a successful company was launched.</p>

<p>I love this story on a couple of different levels.  First, as a professor I take pride in the success and accomplishments of my students even after they leave the campus.  As an alum and faculty member of a college that counts community as one of its defining characteristics, it is great to find other organizations that lift up community as a differentiator.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Applied Math and Physics]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/22/applied-math-and-physics/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-22T11:38:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/22/applied-math-and-physics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know those yellow lines on the football field?  They are harder to draw than they look.  Think for a minute about all of the different field conditions.  Natural green turf, artificial turf, mud, snow, cold brown grass.  Now think about all of the different colored uniforms the players wear.  Now, look closely.  The line never covers up any part of a player, or the ball.  Notice that?  The ball doesn&rsquo;t have a yellow strip, the ball blocks out the yellow line.  The same with players shoes.  Today we got to learn about the yellow lines, the blue lines, the down and distance information,  and many more cool effects that Sportvision puts on our television screens.</p>

<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/SportVision2.jpg" alt="SportVision" /></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the group on the &ldquo;practice Field&rdquo;  They were moving the blue and the yellow line for us as we stood there. You can kind of see them on the big screen on the wall.  The rack of equipment behind me is what they need to bring to each game, and the computers on the desk are whats used by the operator during the game.  The operator can adjust all sorts of parameters based on field conditions and uniform colors etc.  In addition, in the case of a really bad snow storm, they can also project all the yard markers on top of the snow so the people at home have a better view of the field than the players.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In addition to football, Sportvision is also a big provider of on screen information for NASCAR and Major League Baseball.  In the case of NASCAR they display a box of statistics right above the car as it goes around the track.  For Major League Baseball, they show the ball and strike zone, and a bunch of statistics about pitch placement.  They also collect statistics about every player on the diamond.  They track the ball and the players using an array of cameras placed around the ballpark.  Here&rsquo;s where the cool math and physics comes in.  Based on the flight of the ball, they compute the spin!  The cameras are not good enough yet to track the laces, but with some math, they can provide a visualization of how the ball is spinning!  Very cool.</p>

<p>Sportvision is looking at lots of sports, and looking at newer ways to get more information about every player.  For example Football players may have special chips embedded in their shoulder pads someday in the future.  NASCAR cars already have a special box in them that tracks all kinds of information for Sportvision, Soccer players are not likely to have any special chips as it would likely inhibit their play, unless something could be put in their shoes.</p>

<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/SportVision1.jpg" alt="SportVision" /></p>

<p>Like most of the companies we have met with Big Data is an important part of Sportvision&rsquo;s  future plans.  Right now their main customers are the television networks, but in the future individual teams will pay for data.  One interesting aspect of the big data strategy for Sportvision is that they don&rsquo;t have to productize the analytics part of it. The reason is because most teams just want the data, and they consider the analytics to be a competitive advantage.  This doesn&rsquo;t mean that Sportvision won&rsquo;t productize some analysis software, because there is a market at the college level and below where teams can&rsquo;t afford to pay for their own data scientists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JTerm 2014 - Day 1 at Amazon]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T18:08:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jeff Bezos likes to talk about technology and civilization and where we are at in terms of the analogy that we are still at &ldquo;Day One.&rdquo;  He recently observed that we are so early in Day One that the alarm clock hasn&rsquo;t even gone off yet.</p>

<blockquote><p>With new technologies, it’s very tempting to think that you’re further along than you are. But usually, you’re more primitive than you think. My guess is we’re still pretty primitive. We as a society, as a civilization. I doubt we have figured out the new technologies very well yet. At Amazon, we’re doing our part in trying to push things forward, but I have the feeling it’s Day One.</p></blockquote>

<p>And so it was that we found ourselves in the building called Day One South, meeting with our very gracious host Sam. This was a great way to start, and although Sam had not been prompted in any way about what to say, he hit on some of key themes for the students to take away from the course:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Passion</strong> &mdash; You are going to work long hours, so you want to find a place to work and a job to do at that place where you are passionate about whatever it is.  If you aren&rsquo;t excited about it, keep looking.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Culture</strong> &mdash; This part of the discussion brought back both great memories and ulcers in my stomach from the days when Amazon was a Net Perceptions customer.  I&rsquo;ve never been pushed harder than I was by Jennifer Jacobi (JJ) when she was my primary contact at Amazon.  She challenged us, held our feet to the fire, threatened to dump us, and ultimately helped us create a better product.  Apparently this is how Amazon treats all its suppliers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Risk</strong> &mdash; High tech companies are full of risk takers.  Sam was no exception as a young graduate who simply moved to Seattle in search of a job.  Years later he is still at Amazon.  Many more years later than he expected.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/Amazon.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After our meeting with Amazon we found a coffee shop where we could take over a large table and had some group discussion.  I told my own story of Net Perceptions, which I should probably write down here soon, and tried to relate my own experience with the themes I want the students to look for over the next three weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Envisioning the Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/08/envisioning-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T13:38:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2014/01/08/envisioning-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a big day.  The Microsoft mother ship.</p>

<p>We began our visit with an hour in the Envisioning Center, this is Microsoft&rsquo;s take on the future, 5 years out.  There was some pretty cool stuff in there.  If you&rsquo;ve ever drooled over the fancy table on Hawaii Five-O where they can flick things from phone to table, table to screen, etc. You have a pretty good idea of where Microsoft thinks the workplace of the future is headed.  I&rsquo;m there, I want it.  I&rsquo;m already imagining myself walking into the classroom, iPad in hand, and flicking a copy of where we left off last class from my iPad to the board.  Wait, thats a bit of a mixed vision, I&rsquo;m pretty sure they were surface pads, not iPads.  But you get the idea.</p>

<p>After the Envisioning center we moved to another of the 128 buildings on the Microsoft campus where we had time to have our daily group meeting and book presentation.  We were escorted by Tina Wang, and she joined in to the discussion of Sara Lacy&rsquo;s Once you&rsquo;re Lucky, Twice you&rsquo;re good.  Tina works as part of Enwe&rsquo;s group, but is the only one here in the US.  After our lunch we had a really fun talk with Neil Leslie, who shared a lot of wisdom with the group.  And finally Dave Maltz joined us for a final hour on scaling up the data center.  Its fair to say that by the time Dave was done everyone had soaked up about as much information as is possible for brain to take in one day.</p>

<p>A couple observations.  This is not the Microsoft of the 90&rsquo;s.  The Microsoft that I knew and worked with at Net Perceptions were, well, to be blunt, they were bullies back then, because they could be.  I get a real sense that is gone.  Instead they talk of change, how they need to compete, and if you&rsquo;re comfortable, you shouldn&rsquo;t be there.</p>

<p>Returning to key themes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Passion:  I don&rsquo;t think I need to say more about this.</li>
<li>Projects:  I&rsquo;ve told my seniors this for a few years now, but it has a lot more credibility coming from an outsider.  You need to have a project to show when you go to interview.  Bring an app you have built on your phone.  Show a website you have developed on the browser.  Be prepared to talk about the challenges, trade-offs, and succeesses you have had in developing your project.</li>
<li>Linked In:  This is a critical tool for finding a job.  If you are a CS junior or senior and have not created a LinkedIn profile.  Do it now.</li>
<li>Failure:  We heard a lot of stories about failure today, and we will continue to hear of them.  Startups, started and &lsquo;buried,&rsquo; products and projects that failed and never saw the light of day.  The most important message, that I hope students get from this trip, and talking to a bunch of successful people, is that failure is OK.  <strong>Fail Fast</strong>, and learn from your mistakes.  It is a cliche to say that you learn more from failure than success, but it is true.</li>
</ul>


<p>In the evening it was fun to unwind with our first group dinner.  We met up with recent Luther Alum Jake Nowosatka at Cutters Crabhouse.  Its at the far end of Pike Place Market.</p>

<p><img src="/images/JTerm14/PikePlace.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And Now it can be told]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loyal readers will remember that last summer we cruised to Alaska, and some very secretive things were happening on that cruise that I could only refer to rather cryptically.  Well, with the airing of last nights episode of Top Chef the story can now be told.</p>




<p><p>We were on the set for the filming of the Quickfire challenge onboard the ship!  Although the filming took several hours, we got less than 1 second of screen time.  But here we are!  Brian and I happened to be in a pretty good spot as the camera flashes past us several times.  The ladies we were talking to turned out to be from Wisconsin, in fact from right by our cabin!  The two in the print shirts actually got an additional 2 seconds of screen time along with their comments on the food.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8433342727" title="View 'IMG_0276' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0276" alt="IMG_0276" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8354/8433342727_68204d7fdd.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>Jane, Brian, and I all made it on again towards the end of the challenge.  Sadly there is no sign of Holly.
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8434428742" title="View 'IMG_0277' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0277" alt="IMG_0277" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8355/8434428742_32af448c8b.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p><p>Of course since this was all way before the show started we had no idea who any of the chefs really were.  I do remember really liking Sheldon&rsquo;s lettuce cups as well as Stefan&rsquo;s little potato soup cup.  I could swear that I remember seeing Kristin on the ship, so maybe she got to come along since she would be competing in last chance kitchen in Juneau. </p></p>

<p><p>Right now I&rsquo;m looking forward to the finale.  I&rsquo;m not sure who I want to win the most, with Stefan and Josie gone all the villains are off the show.  I think it would be awesome if Kristin makes it through LCK and gets to compete against Sheldon or Josh in the Finale.  Thats Josh, by the way, in the first photo.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
