<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-09T11:52:54-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JTerm 2014 - Day 1 at Amazon]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T17:08:03-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/jterm-2014-day-1-at-amazon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jeff Bezos likes to talk about technology and civilization and where we are at in terms of the analogy that we are still at &ldquo;Day One.&rdquo;  He recently observed that we are so early in Day One that the alarm clock hasn&rsquo;t even gone off yet.</p>

<blockquote><p>With new technologies, it’s very tempting to think that you’re further along than you are. But usually, you’re more primitive than you think. My guess is we’re still pretty primitive. We as a society, as a civilization. I doubt we have figured out the new technologies very well yet. At Amazon, we’re doing our part in trying to push things forward, but I have the feeling it’s Day One.</p></blockquote>

<p>And so it was that we found ourselves in the building called Day One South, meeting with our very gracious host Sam. This was a great way to start, and although Sam had not been prompted in any way about what to say, he hit on some of key themes for the students to take away from the course:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Passion</strong> &mdash; You are going to work long hours, so you want to find a place to work and a job to do at that place where you are passionate about whatever it is.  If you aren&rsquo;t excited about it, keep looking.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Culture</strong> &mdash; This part of the discussion brought back both great memories and ulcers in my stomach from the days when Amazon was a Net Perceptions customer.  I&rsquo;ve never been pushed harder than I was by Jennifer Jacobi (JJ) when she was my primary contact at Amazon.  She challenged us, held our feet to the fire, threatened to dump us, and ultimately helped us create a better product.  Apparently this is how Amazon treats all its suppliers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Risk</strong> &mdash; High tech companies are full of risk takers.  Sam was no exception as a young graduate who simply moved to Seattle in search of a job.  Years later he is still at Amazon.  Many more years later than he expected.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>After our meeting with Amazon we found a coffee shop where we could take over a large table and had some group discussion.  I told my own story of Net Perceptions, which I should probably write down here soon, and tried to relate my own experience with the themes I want the students to look for over the next three weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And Now It Can Be Told]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/and-now-it-can-be-told</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loyal readers will remember that last summer we cruised to Alaska, and some very secretive things were happening on that cruise that I could only refer to rather cryptically.  Well, with the airing of last nights episode of Top Chef the story can now be told.</p>




<p><p>We were on the set for the filming of the Quickfire challenge onboard the ship!  Although the filming took several hours, we got less than 1 second of screen time.  But here we are!  Brian and I happened to be in a pretty good spot as the camera flashes past us several times.  The ladies we were talking to turned out to be from Wisconsin, in fact from right by our cabin!  The two in the print shirts actually got an additional 2 seconds of screen time along with their comments on the food.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8433342727" title="View 'IMG_0276' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0276" alt="IMG_0276" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8354/8433342727_68204d7fdd.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>Jane, Brian, and I all made it on again towards the end of the challenge.  Sadly there is no sign of Holly.
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/71706244@N00/8434428742" title="View 'IMG_0277' on Flickr.com"><img height="375" title="IMG_0277" alt="IMG_0277" border="0" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8355/8434428742_32af448c8b.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p><p>Of course since this was all way before the show started we had no idea who any of the chefs really were.  I do remember really liking Sheldon&rsquo;s lettuce cups as well as Stefan&rsquo;s little potato soup cup.  I could swear that I remember seeing Kristin on the ship, so maybe she got to come along since she would be competing in last chance kitchen in Juneau. </p></p>

<p><p>Right now I&rsquo;m looking forward to the finale.  I&rsquo;m not sure who I want to win the most, with Stefan and Josie gone all the villains are off the show.  I think it would be awesome if Kristin makes it through LCK and gets to compete against Sheldon or Josh in the Finale.  Thats Josh, by the way, in the first photo.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
