<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>A Reputable Journal (Education)</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 21:31:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Version 3.0 of Runestone Interactive released</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/08/runestone-interactive-3-0.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm pleased to announce that over the weekend, I updated &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt; to version 3.0.  This release completes another summer of hacking, and integrating contributions from colleagues around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan in this post is to briefly summarize some of the highlights of the new release and then follow up over the course of this week with posts and screencasts about specific features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progress tracking, and cohorts.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is one of the major visual changes to the books, thanks to some great work by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ivipul.com"&gt;Vipul Thackur&lt;/a&gt;.  The "chapters" have been broken up into subchapters and you can now track your progress through each chapter/sub-chapter on the table of contents.  In addition, there is now the facility to create a study group and to negotiate reading deadlines and have discussions with members of your own cohort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New and improved grading and assignments interface.&lt;/strong&gt;  Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://presnick.people.si.umich.edu/"&gt;Paul Resnick&lt;/a&gt; and his students at the University of Michigan you can now group activities into assignments.  You can also provide comments to students on the programming problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom assignment page.&lt;/strong&gt;  As an instructor you can now easily edit an assignments page that is part of your custom course.  This page will allow you to make use of all of the features of the Runestone tools and restructured text to add your own assignments.  I think this feature has great potential to grow into additional custom content in the future so stay tuned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run in Codelens.&lt;/strong&gt;  Sometime earlier this summer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pgbovine.net/"&gt;Philip Guo&lt;/a&gt; added an iframe interface to the awesome Online Python Tutor.  This allowed me to add a button to most of the activecode examples that allow you to also run the example in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pythontutor.com"&gt;Online Python Tutor&lt;/a&gt;.  You can edit the examples and click the button to run another version.  This feature requires that you have internet access while reading, something I have resisted in the past, but it it seems increasingly difficult to be offline now anyway, so I'm not going to resist anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Coach.&lt;/strong&gt;   Last spring at SIGCSE, Paul Resnick, David Ranum and I spent an afternoon hacking.  The idea was to provide an interface that would allow students to look at the history of any particular programming assignment, and see the differences from one try to the next.  Our hypothesis is that this would be a good teaching tool for an instructor to use with a student to review how they developed a solution and arrived at their current state.  I expanded on the concept a bit this summer by making use of pylint, which points out a number of potential problems that plague beginning programmers.  For example, pointing out "useless statements" when a student forgets their parenthesis on a function call.  My hope is that Code Coach will grow into a fully automated code tutor in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockly directive.&lt;/strong&gt;   I think that blocks based programming languages like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blockly-demo.appspot.com/static/apps/index.html"&gt;Blockly&lt;/a&gt;, and Scratch have great potential to help students develop a mental model or a picture in their mind of how various programming constructs work. So I created this new directive that will let you write blocks language examples and exercises.  My hope was to write a new introduction to How to Think Like a Computer Scientist using Blockly, but there are only so many hours in the summer.  Hopefully I'll make progress on this during the coming months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activecode support for Javascript and HTML.&lt;/strong&gt;  In preparation for a new course I'm teaching this fall, I wanted to be able to have students edit HTML and Javascript examples like we can do with Python.  Now you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Book:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/pip/index.html"&gt;Programs, Information, People&lt;/a&gt;.  This book is a new mashup of the How to Think book that Paul Resnick uses in his course in the School of Information by the same title.  I think this is a great alternative to the How to Think book in that it avoids some of the "early math" problems and focuses on information processing using data from the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AP Java Review:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/JavaReview/index.html"&gt;This book&lt;/a&gt; came on line last spring, but its worth mentioning in this summary.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cc.gatech.edu/people/barbara-ericson"&gt;Barbara Ericson&lt;/a&gt; at Georgia Tech has put this together and although we can't run any Java examples in the browser the rest of the interactive resources are great for getting ready for the AP exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thats the overview.  I look forward to bringing you the details over the next week.  In the meantime, you can see some of the features on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/overview/overview.html"&gt;Overview site&lt;/a&gt;  I'm sure we will see a few glitches as these new features move out of beta testing and into general use. Please report them on our &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/bnmnetp/runestone"&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt; or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/08/runestone-interactive-3-0.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:55:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why MOOCs? Why not?</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/why-moocs-why-not.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to include a link here to my latest post on Luther's Ideas and Creations blog.  Its just some thoughts and questions I had on MOOCs and online education at Luther College.  &lt;a href="https://www.luther.edu/ideas-creations-blog/?story_id=541741"&gt;Why Moocs? Why Not?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Education</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/why-moocs-why-not.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 05:00:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Think like a Computer Scientist Interactive Edition</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2012/07/how-to-think-like-a-computer-scientist-interactive-edition.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After hosting the interactive edition of How to Think like a Computer Scientist on the Google app engine at thinkcspy.appspot.com for over a year, we finally made the switchover to a new domain.  As of today all requests to thinkcspy will be automatically redirected to &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;http://interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new domain, is hosted by Webfaction.com.  They have very reasonable hosting rates, along with plenty of bandwidth and disk space.   I have more control over the development platform that I use, I get to keep my data in a real relational database (postgresql) where I can write queries and export my data as much as I want, and finally, if I ever need to move from Webfaction, I own the domain and can move it with me, and I won't need to go through this name change again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have used the thinkcspy site, you will notice a few upgrades to the content of the book have taken place.  In addition, we are now hosting another book along side thinkcspy.  So we now have coverage for both CS1 and CS2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS1 -- &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/courselib/static/thinkcspy/index.html"&gt;http://interactivepython.org/courselib/static/thinkcspy/index.html&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS2 --&lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/courselib/static/pythonds/index.html"&gt; http://interactivepython.org/courselib/static/pythonds/index.html&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS2 book is based on our paperback book, Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python by Brad Miller and David Ranum.  Our forward thinking publisher has given us permission to convert the paper book into an interactive version and make it available online!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other great thing about the move to interactivepython.org is that you can now host your own course.  That is you can use one of our books online, but you are the instructor, so you can grade homework assignments, and look at activity reports for the students in your class.  So far we have 20 different institutions hosting one of the two books for a course currently,  or for the upcoming fall term.  The links to create your own course are right there on the home page, so if you are interested in using this site for a course go right ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one downside to this move is that I did not migrate any of the data from the old thinkcspy site.  So if you have saved programs there you will need to recreate them at the new site.  I gave people plenty of notice about the move, so I'm hoping this won't turn into a big issue.  If it is, let me know, and I'll try to pull your code out of the google datastore for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second issue with the move is that I don't use google accounts  anymore.  If you want to save your programs you will need to create an account on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a link to thinkcspy.appspot.com on any pages you control, please make the change to point to the new domain and location.  Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in contributing to the project, have a book you would like to host, or are just interested in how we are doing this, you can check out the code on github:  http://github.com/bnmnetp/runestone   If you don't want to go that far, but have assignments, or assessment questions you would like to contribute, please contact me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2012/07/how-to-think-like-a-computer-scientist-interactive-edition.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Runestone Interactive</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2012/06/runestone-interactive.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What a week its been!   So much has happened in the last week that I just have to take some time out to organize my thoughts and get some of this information out there where others can read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;What is Runestone Interactive?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Runestone Interactive is primarily a home for both the content and the technologies that go into publishing interactive textbooks.  At the moment interactive textbooks for Computer Science, but who knows how far this could go.  Probably the best way to see this is to actually visit our site and play around.  But in the meantime here is a short video to give you an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Us4fpoNht68" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Home to our open source publishing tools.  My goal as that these tools become the LaTeX of interactive publishing. There is lots of work to do before we can claim success here, but I think we have a good vision and a decent start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model for a new online only publishing house. At some point, I think it is important for content to go through an editorial process, not just for copy editing quality, but for coherence, and quality of approach. Right now the number of content creators using our system is pretty small, but I can already see that starting to grow. We have lots of thinking to do about this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A home for hosting online courses or textbooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Who is your audience?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I think we serve three distinct groups of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The  teacher out there who wants a good quality textbook, but is not interested in forcing their students to pay $100+ and is interesting in trying an interactive book, all for free.   So to serve this audience we have &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;interactvepython.org&lt;/a&gt;. You can select one of our pre-defined books and set up a course where you are the instructor and have access to grading etc. Or you can use the drag-and-drop interface to put together a book by selecting from the library of modules. Maybe some of these teachers have an exercise or two they would like to contribute, but mostly they are just looking for good materials to help them with their course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors who would like to contribute significant chunks of content -- chapters or section sized -- or videos. For example I'm working with an entrepreneur who wants to add content and a graphics package that looks more like Nodebox. He's very interested in putting together materials for middle school kids.  Others, including other Computer Science researchers, are more interested in algorithm visualization and working together on building in more visualization tools to the tool box.  Others have their own CS course materials that they would like to get into an interactive form and make available to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who are interested in learning CS on their own.  We get a ton of people coming to the site just to learn on their own. I had the most heartfelt letter from a guy the other day who found our site as he is trying to retool after being laid off for a couple of years. He said this is the first thing he's come across that really worked for him and helped him learn a bit of CS.  How does this compare with Udacity and Coursera?  Both of those companies are primarily video oriented, and both of those companies are running courses that are in some sense synchronous.  You have to move through the course on their schedule to get the full benefit.  Our books/courses can be done at your own pace, on your own time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;I would like to use this for my own class how do I get started?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its easy, just follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to&lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt; interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt; and register yourself as a user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on Create a Custom Course link in the right sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a short name for your course that uniquely identifies it among all the other courses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in a short description for your course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you get to choose.  Do you want to use one of our standard configurations, either How to Think Like a Computer Scientist: Interactive Edition, or Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python  or do you want to build a custom book by choosing modules from both of the above?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the build button.  Wait a few minutes and you will have a page with a link to your new course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now you can send your students to interactivepython.org and simply tell them to register for your course.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Why would you choose to build your own course when you could just use one of the open books?  When you create your own course you become the instructor and admin for that course.  You can grade your students assignments right online, and even access their homework in progress if they have questions.  You can also get a sense for the different activities they are choosing to use in the textbook.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How can I get involved?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways you can get involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We need readers who are willing to be critical and report bugs on everything from typos to activecode blocks that don't work exactly right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need web developers who are willing to work on the back end, developing reports for instructors and making sure our infrastructure is sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need web developers who are interested in developing user facing features, everything from algorithm visualizations to interactive assessment tools like the multiple choice and fill in the blank questions you see already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need compiler geeks who can help fix bugs in our Javascript implementation of Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need authors who want to add new and interesting content, either entire courses, or new modules that could be combined with the modules already there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2012/06/runestone-interactive.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Think Like a Computer Scientist - Interactive Edition</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2011/09/how-to-think-like-a-computer-scientist-interactive-edition.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its fun to see my sabbatical project getting loose the wild.  It is always a bit scary to work on something creative and new and then let other people play with it and respond to it.  Such is the case with the new eBook I worked on during my sabbatical.  Unlike other eBooks that you may be aware of,  this book -- in the words of Emeril -- "kicks it up a notch".  Using some cool open source javascript code that I've had to modify and bend a bit for my own use this book allows the reader to try their hand at Python right in the book.  Examples are fully runnable in two different ways.  Each section has an accompanying video.  My co-author, David Ranum and I are using this book in class this Fall and its fun to see how the students interact with the book.  We've had none of the usual Fall frustration at getting Python installed on students machines.  You can have a look at the book &lt;a href="http://thinkcspy.appspot.com"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Note, you'll need a good modern browser, and a gmail account.  We've had the best success with Chrome and Safari.  Firefox 6 works but seems  a little flakey at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Phil Wagner posted a nice little writeup about our project on his BrokenAirplane &lt;a href="http://www.brokenairplane.com/2011/09/updated-python-how-to-think-like.html"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told Phil, this book is really a triumph of open source.  Here are the open source components we've used and modified for this project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The text in the book is based on the original How to Think Like a Computer Scientist by Jeff Elkner, et. al.  You can find the non-interactive version &lt;a href="http://openbookproject.net/thinkcs/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Python Interpreter is By Scott Graham and you can find out information about it at &lt;a href="http://skulpt.org"&gt;Skulpt.org&lt;/a&gt;.  This was a really key piece and although I've spent a ton of time creating a turtle graphics module for it, the book wouldn't have gotten off the ground without it.  In the book the pieces we refer to as activecode  all make use of sculpt, along with the really nice javascript editor &lt;a href="http://codemirror.net"&gt;Codemirror&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What we call codelens in the book is based on work by &lt;a href="http://people.csail.mit.edu/pgbovine/python/"&gt;Philip Guo&lt;/a&gt;.  I really like this part because students can step through the code a line at a time both forward and backward.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, the glue that holds the whole thing together is the excellent &lt;a href="http://sphinx.pocoo.org/"&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; publishing system.  This really turned out to be the key as Sphinx lets you create new directives to use in writing.   I was able to add directives to sphinx to make it really easy to include the interactive features without getting in the way of the writing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really think this Interactive Edition has huge possibilities for the future, I can see incorporating many other interesting kinds of visualizations, and video collections.  My future todo list is already very large, and I'm anxious to hear ideas from others as they use the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="blogger-post-footer"&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-726200996429097574?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com" alt=""&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2011/09/how-to-think-like-a-computer-scientist-interactive-edition.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>