<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>A Reputable Journal (Python)</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 22:41:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Runestone Fall 2014</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/09/runestone-fall-report.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;School is underway again, and now that we are a few weeks in to the semester I wanted to take a minute to talk about growth.  Last year about this time things were still pretty chaotic, with the unexpected success of the books the servers were laboring intensely to keep up with all of the new users.   This necessitated a weekend switch to a larger server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="growth"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Google Analytics is showing that our daily traffic has doubled from last fall!  Here's a comparison to a year ago, adjusting for the days of the week to be the same.  Its amazing how consistent the weekly pattern is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/fall2014growth.png" src="http://reputablejournal.com/images/fall2014growth.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="code-coach"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code Coach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the new features in our 3.x release is the Code Coach.  You have probably noticed that button in some exercises, or some of the examples.  Code Coach is in its very early stages as a platform for providing students with intelligent automated feedback on their code.  I think this has &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; potential, but is going to require a lot of resources to bring to fruition.  Right now there are two things going on that I think do add value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every time the student presses the run button that version of the code is saved.  Code Coach lets a student move backward and forward through their history to view the differences between one version of the code and the next.  I can see this as a very valuable teaching tool for an instructor to use with the student.  I've looked at a bunch of these and its amazing how often a student gets off in the weeds over a very simple project and ends up throwing away a huge amount of work, or just making random changes.  I would really like to have the conversation where I can show the student, if you would have fixed this, you would not have had to delete all of this other stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everytime the student runs a program, I run Pylint on it in the background.  Pylint catches all sorts of "errors" that do not show up as Python runtime errors.  One big one is forgetting parentheses.  I've seen this so many times:  &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;myTurtle.forward&lt;/tt&gt; this is not a runtime error because Python evaluates the statement to simply be a reference to a function.  But the student can't see it.  "Dr. Miller, I don't get any errors, but my turtle isn't doing anything, what am I doing wrong?"  Pylint flags this for the useless statement that it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really looking forward to applying much more advanced analysis to the code in order to provide better coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/09/runestone-fall-report.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 19:57:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Version 3.0 of Runestone Interactive released</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/08/runestone-interactive-3-0.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm pleased to announce that over the weekend, I updated &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt; to version 3.0.  This release completes another summer of hacking, and integrating contributions from colleagues around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan in this post is to briefly summarize some of the highlights of the new release and then follow up over the course of this week with posts and screencasts about specific features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progress tracking, and cohorts.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is one of the major visual changes to the books, thanks to some great work by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ivipul.com"&gt;Vipul Thackur&lt;/a&gt;.  The "chapters" have been broken up into subchapters and you can now track your progress through each chapter/sub-chapter on the table of contents.  In addition, there is now the facility to create a study group and to negotiate reading deadlines and have discussions with members of your own cohort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New and improved grading and assignments interface.&lt;/strong&gt;  Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://presnick.people.si.umich.edu/"&gt;Paul Resnick&lt;/a&gt; and his students at the University of Michigan you can now group activities into assignments.  You can also provide comments to students on the programming problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom assignment page.&lt;/strong&gt;  As an instructor you can now easily edit an assignments page that is part of your custom course.  This page will allow you to make use of all of the features of the Runestone tools and restructured text to add your own assignments.  I think this feature has great potential to grow into additional custom content in the future so stay tuned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run in Codelens.&lt;/strong&gt;  Sometime earlier this summer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pgbovine.net/"&gt;Philip Guo&lt;/a&gt; added an iframe interface to the awesome Online Python Tutor.  This allowed me to add a button to most of the activecode examples that allow you to also run the example in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pythontutor.com"&gt;Online Python Tutor&lt;/a&gt;.  You can edit the examples and click the button to run another version.  This feature requires that you have internet access while reading, something I have resisted in the past, but it it seems increasingly difficult to be offline now anyway, so I'm not going to resist anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Coach.&lt;/strong&gt;   Last spring at SIGCSE, Paul Resnick, David Ranum and I spent an afternoon hacking.  The idea was to provide an interface that would allow students to look at the history of any particular programming assignment, and see the differences from one try to the next.  Our hypothesis is that this would be a good teaching tool for an instructor to use with a student to review how they developed a solution and arrived at their current state.  I expanded on the concept a bit this summer by making use of pylint, which points out a number of potential problems that plague beginning programmers.  For example, pointing out "useless statements" when a student forgets their parenthesis on a function call.  My hope is that Code Coach will grow into a fully automated code tutor in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockly directive.&lt;/strong&gt;   I think that blocks based programming languages like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blockly-demo.appspot.com/static/apps/index.html"&gt;Blockly&lt;/a&gt;, and Scratch have great potential to help students develop a mental model or a picture in their mind of how various programming constructs work. So I created this new directive that will let you write blocks language examples and exercises.  My hope was to write a new introduction to How to Think Like a Computer Scientist using Blockly, but there are only so many hours in the summer.  Hopefully I'll make progress on this during the coming months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activecode support for Javascript and HTML.&lt;/strong&gt;  In preparation for a new course I'm teaching this fall, I wanted to be able to have students edit HTML and Javascript examples like we can do with Python.  Now you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Book:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/pip/index.html"&gt;Programs, Information, People&lt;/a&gt;.  This book is a new mashup of the How to Think book that Paul Resnick uses in his course in the School of Information by the same title.  I think this is a great alternative to the How to Think book in that it avoids some of the "early math" problems and focuses on information processing using data from the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AP Java Review:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/JavaReview/index.html"&gt;This book&lt;/a&gt; came on line last spring, but its worth mentioning in this summary.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cc.gatech.edu/people/barbara-ericson"&gt;Barbara Ericson&lt;/a&gt; at Georgia Tech has put this together and although we can't run any Java examples in the browser the rest of the interactive resources are great for getting ready for the AP exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thats the overview.  I look forward to bringing you the details over the next week.  In the meantime, you can see some of the features on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/overview/overview.html"&gt;Overview site&lt;/a&gt;  I'm sure we will see a few glitches as these new features move out of beta testing and into general use. Please report them on our &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/bnmnetp/runestone"&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt; or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/08/runestone-interactive-3-0.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:55:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PyCon 2014 Keynote Shout Out</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/pycon-2014-keynote-shout-out.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am going to have to go to PyCon.  Not next year, as I'm going to be in Malta at the time, but hopefully in 2016.  I don't know how many people attend, but the number is big, and they have sold old every year for the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just got done watching one of the Keynote presentations online from PyCon 2014 held in Montreal April 9-17.  I'm linking to it below, because it goes right to the heart of most of my academic work.  But, it was especially exciting at the 20:05 mark.  Where she highlights &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://skulpt.org"&gt;Skulpt&lt;/a&gt; projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/4QOoAw6Su7M?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/pycon-2014-keynote-shout-out.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 14:20:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moving to Nikola</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/moving-to-nikola.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I moved this blog to Octopress in January, it was inspiring in many ways.  There were two things that slightly bugged me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octopress is entirely too ruby based.  Rake, and all of that made me feel bad, like I was cheating on Python.  Surely there must be a similar tool in the Python world I thought to myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octopress uses markdown.  I really like my restructuredText, and its just a bit irritating to have to think about the differences when I want to do a blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this weekend I found a couple of new static blog site generators that &lt;strong&gt;were&lt;/strong&gt; python based, and after playing around with Pelican, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://getnikola.com"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; I settled on the move to Nikola.  I really like the image galleries and slideshows that are built in, and I feel like I can jump in and start hacking if something develops that I really want to change.  Plus, having already hacked a bunch of restructuredText directives, I know I can extend my blogging tool to do all kinds of fun things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/04/moving-to-nikola.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 17:38:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Easy Publishing with Runestone Interactive</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/03/easy-publishing-with-runestone-interactive.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my January travels, I also converted this blog from tubmlr, which had been frustrating me for a while, to Octopress, with which I have been very happy.  Nothing like hacker level control of your own blog.  But more, than just the switch in tools, the move to Octopress inspired me to make it easier for people to publish small or large works using the Runestone tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, at the Learning @ Scale conference we demoed this new capability.  See &lt;a href="http://runestoneinteractive.org/LearningAtScal"&gt;the demo here&lt;/a&gt;.  To make it super easy to publish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lecture slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab Instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In class exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A short module on your favorite topic not covered elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An entire book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="more"&gt;&lt;a href="http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/03/easy-publishing-with-runestone-interactive.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><category>Runestone</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2014/03/easy-publishing-with-runestone-interactive.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 05:00:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Runestone Interactive Announces New Editions of Interactive Textbooks</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/08/runestone-interactive-announces-new-editions-of-interactive-textbooks.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I'm really pleased to announce that  have launched version 2.0 of our interactive computer science  textbooks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/thinkcspy/index.html"&gt;How to Think Like a Computer Scientist:  Interactive Edition 2.0&lt;/a&gt;  (CS 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/pythonds/index.html"&gt;Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python&lt;/a&gt;  (CS 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first launched these books on our &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;interactivepython.org&lt;/a&gt; website in May of 2012, after around a year of private testing in the classroom.  Since then we have had 1.3 million page views by a quarter of a million unique visitors.  Daily, we get around 2,000 unique visitors.  Not bad for a site with zero dollars for an advertising budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What Makes these Books Unique?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These books are unique because they are interactive.  We have developed a set of authoring tools that make it really easy to write an interactive textbook with many interactive features.  We call these the Runestone tools.  Some of the interactive features that are possible include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activecode&lt;/strong&gt;:  Using a &lt;a href="http://skulpt.org"&gt;Javascript implementation&lt;/a&gt; of Python you can run and modify the examples in the textbook right in the book.  No server connection is required since it is based on javascript and runs right in the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Codelens&lt;/strong&gt;:  Using the amazing power of the &lt;a href="http://www.pythontutor.com"&gt;pythontutor.com&lt;/a&gt;  tools you can step through examples one line at a time, forward and backward.  While you are stepping through the code you can see variables and other data structures change values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parsons Problems: &lt;/strong&gt; For beginning programmers Parson's problems are like refrigerator magnet poetry.  You can provide your students with the statements needed to write a program, but they must put the statements in the correct order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline Quizzes: &lt;/strong&gt;Each section of the book contains some inline quizzes that allow students to check their understanding of the material.  The quizzes have different feedback for each correct or incorrect answer that try to point students in the right direction. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Homework:&lt;/strong&gt;   At the end of each chapter are programming assignments.  In this new edition we have provided the answers to the odd numbered questions, and discussion forums for students to exchange ideas or ask questions about the homework problems.  As an instructor, you can grade your students programs on one convenient page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlighting&lt;/strong&gt;  This is another much requested new feature.  Students can highlight text using the mouse and the highlights magically reappear on any supported browser.  In addition we will remember the students last location in the book and offer to return them to that position when they return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many other features but the best way to understand what we are doing is to actually have a look at our &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/overview/overview.html"&gt;overview page&lt;/a&gt;, which shows everything I have mentioned here and a lot more in action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over this past year we have discovered that we serve two different audiences with these books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructors looking for a textbook to use in their own course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who are interested in teaching themselves some computer science and have found our books through google search, the Python wiki, or some other word of mouth source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Textbooks as a Service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we launched the site last year we decided to not only provide the books free and open for anyone who wanted to read them, but also as a service for instructors who wanted to have their own custom copy of the book where they could track their students progress, review their answers to quizzes, and grade their students homework.   If you want to use our books in your class you are welcome to do so.  You have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use a copy of either book as is with the order of the chapters just as they are on the books linked to above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can try our custom interface where you can mix and match chapters from both books to create your own custom textbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have created your own course then you will be able to see the assignments your students have completed right in the textbook.  I find this to be very valuable as an instructor.  For example if I have assigned the students to read and do the quizzes for a particular section, I can simply go to the quiz question and click on the 'Compare Me' button.  As an instructor I will see a summary of the answers my students gave, as well as the details of the answers that each student tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Supporting the Independent Learner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest surprise of this project is the number of people that have found one of the books through google, and are simply teaching themselves to program.  We are hopeful that some of the new features we have added will help foster a  community of learners so that people just learning to program can talk to others in the same situation.  Some things we hope are particularly helpful include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answers to odd numbered questions&lt;/strong&gt;.  This was probably the number one request I got through email all last year.  How do I know if I did it right?  We decided to risk it and provide the answers, but only to the odd numbered problems.  In addition a student must try to answer the problem at least once before the answer becomes "unlocked"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion threads&lt;/strong&gt; for homework problems.  Again this may seem like a risky move where students can just publish their answer and others can copy.  But, what we are hoping for is that students will see that there are many ways to get to the "right answer"  There are different approaches and programming styles that can be used to solve the same problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare Me&lt;/strong&gt;  Although we aren't sure about the title on the button, the idea is that after answering one of the quiz questions a learner can check on their overall 'grade' for all quiz questions, and see how their answer compared to all the other learners.  We haven't gone so far as to give out badges, but we think this is a nice intermediate approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Runestone Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The books above were built using our &lt;a href="http://runestoneinteractive.org"&gt;Runestone Interactive&lt;/a&gt; toolkit.  These tools are freely available on &lt;a href="http://github.com/bnmnetp/runestone"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.  If you want to write your own interactive book, or even just use the tools to create some interactive labs for your students you are welcome to do so.  You can write your materials in an easy to use markup language called restructuredText and add examples or quizzes using very simple tags.  Complete documentation for our extensions to restructuredText is provided on the website.  In addition to our own books, the team at Harvey Mudd College has published &lt;a href="http://www.cs.hmc.edu/csforall"&gt;CS for All&lt;/a&gt;  another introductory textbook using our tools.  I know of at least two other books in progress!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in following our development or getting involved You can do so in several ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter, follow &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/iRunestone"&gt;iRunestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RunestoneInteractive"&gt;facebook.com/RunestoneInteractive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/runestoneinteractive"&gt;Groups&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to the many people who have provided us with feedback over the last year.  And I am especially grateful to the ACM SIGCSE social projects committee for providing me with a special projects grant that allowed me to work with a student (Isaac Dontje Lindell) this summer.  He did a ton of work and will be graduating next year.  You should hire him.  In addition this project relies on many open source components which I will mention and link to below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The original text for&lt;em&gt; How to Think Like a Computer Scientist&lt;/em&gt; comes from Allen Downey, Jeff Elkner and Chris Meyers.  We have modified it a lot, but without a starting point for us to experiment with our interactive ideas this project never would have taken off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures&lt;/em&gt; text is published as a paper textbook by Franklin Beedle and Associates.  Without the forward thinking of Jim Leisy this book would be stuck.  Thankfully Jim freed us to use the text in an interactive form online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Guzdial, Barbara Ericson and the rest of the &lt;a href="http://home.cc.gatech.edu/csl/CSLearning4U"&gt;CSLearning4U&lt;/a&gt; research group at Georgia Tech have provided questions, assessments,  and many other features and ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Activecode&lt;/strong&gt; examples are made possible by &lt;a href="http://skulpt.org"&gt;skulpt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Codelens&lt;/strong&gt; examples are made possible by Philip Guo and his &lt;a href="http://www.pythontutor.com"&gt;pythontutor.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The look and feel of the book is based on the &lt;a href="http://getbootstrap.com/"&gt;bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The system that builds the website from source is called &lt;a href="http://sphinx-doc.org"&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; and is really the backbone of the system that allows us to write our interactive extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/vkaravir"&gt;Ville Karavirta&lt;/a&gt; wrote the original js-parsons library and Mike Hewner integrated it into the Runestone Tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/08/runestone-interactive-announces-new-editions-of-interactive-textbooks.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Making Python3 my default</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/04/making-python3-my-default.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm finally there.  After a long time of writing books using Python 3, and teaching in Python 3 on a daily basis, I'm finally at the point where I'm changing my work environment to use Python 3 by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the signs that convinced me it was time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The release of Pillow to provide PIL functionality!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django 1.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPython and IPython notebook are fully supported  -- I Love IPython Notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib !!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sphinx, Jinja, SQLAlchemy, and many others are supported.  See: &lt;a href="https://python3wos.appspot.com/"&gt;https://python3wos.appspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of projects that I use a lot that are not yet on Python3 (web2py) but I'm not going to let that stop me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out to be pretty easy to get yourself up and running on all of this stuff with Python 3.  I'm on a Mac running 10.8.3.  The first and most important step is to get a working version of pip for Python3.  First you need to install distribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="plain plain" style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 13px; direction: ltr !important; display: inline !important; color: black !important;"&gt;curl -O &lt;a style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; color: black !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 1em !important; direction: ltr !important;" href="http://python-distribute.org/distribute_setup.py"&gt;http://python-distribute.org/distribute_setup.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="plain plain" style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 13px; direction: ltr !important; display: inline !important; color: black !important;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace; font-size: 13px; line-height: 1.1em; background-color: white; text-align: left; white-space: pre;"&gt;sudo python3 distribute_setup.py&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will install easy_install in your Python home, but go one more step and install pip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="plain plain" style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 13px; direction: ltr !important; display: inline !important; color: black !important;"&gt;curl -O &lt;a style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; color: black !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 1em !important; direction: ltr !important;" href="https://raw.github.com/pypa/pip/master/contrib/get-pip.py"&gt;https://raw.github.com/pypa/pip/master/contrib/get-pip.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="plain plain" style="background-image: none !important; border: 0px !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important; vertical-align: baseline !important; font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace !important; border-top-left-radius: 0px !important; border-top-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-right-radius: 0px !important; border-bottom-left-radius: 0px !important; bottom: auto !important; float: none !important; height: auto !important; left: auto !important; line-height: 1.1em !important; outline: 0px !important; overflow: visible !important; position: static !important; right: auto !important; top: auto !important; width: auto !important; box-sizing: content-box !important; font-size: 13px; direction: ltr !important; display: inline !important; color: black !important;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Consolas, 'Bitstream Vera Sans Mono', 'Courier New', Courier, monospace; font-size: 13px; line-height: 1.1em; background-color: white; text-align: left; white-space: pre;"&gt;sudo python3 get-pip.py&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create a pip in your /Library/Frameworks/Python.framework/Versions/3.3/bin  directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there you can begin pip installing pretty much everything you need!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my history today as I was setting everything up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;10393* pip3 install ipython&lt;br&gt;10409* pip3 install numpy&lt;br&gt;10410* pip3 install matplotlib&lt;br&gt;10429* pip3 install tornado&lt;br&gt;10430* pip3 install pyzmq&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;10455  pip3 install Sphinx&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are on a Mac you will need to use easy_install to install one thing, for IPython.  For some reason pip installing the readline library puts it too late in the load path to work with IPython, so you need to use easy_install-3.3 readline  to get the history in IPython working just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you will want to add the Python 3 bin directory to your PATH.  Edit your .bashrc or .zshenv file.  Note that the following puts the Python 3 bin directory at the front of your PATH, making it the default when you type pip, python, or ipython.  If you need to revert back to python2.7 for some task you will need to be explicit about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;export PATH=/Library/Frameworks/Python.framework/Versions/3.3/bin:$PATH&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy!  You were expecting this to be a long and arduous process fraught with hacks and silly edits to config files.  Nope, just a few basic commands.  I take this as the final sign that Python 3 is here and ready to be your day to day Python.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/04/making-python3-my-default.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>To Infinity and Beyond</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/02/we-passed-3-million-entries-in-our-log-data-for-interactivepython-org-which-got-.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://reputablejournal.com/images/31.media.tumblr.com/9c55cab1486b5c7bb35cf993249f6b4c/tumblr_midzqpGQSy1r729pmo1_1280.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We passed 3 million entries in our log data for &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org"&gt;InteractivePython.org&lt;/a&gt; which got me to wondering about how we are growing.  The site has been live for 275 days.  You can really see how the site took off after day 100, which makes sense because that was bout the time fall classes started around the country.  The tiny plateau between day 225 and 250 corresponds to Christmas/winter break for most schools, and now that Spring semester is in full swing it looks like the slope has gotten steeper again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dotted line is the linear best fit line with a slope of 12,836.7.  Even if our log database is not growing exponentially thats an impressively steep slope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just because this is all about Python and education, here's the Python code that created the graph.  I love matplotlib, it is such a powerful tool for quickly looking at your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
from numpy import polyfit, arange

f = open('bydate','r')
days = f.readlines()
totals = [0]

for d in days:
    day,count = d.split('|')
    count = int(count)
    totals.append(totals[-1]+count)

x = arange(len(totals))
m,b = polyfit(x,totals,1)
print m
plt.plot(x,totals,x,m*x+b, '--k')
plt.ylim(ymin=0)
plt.show()
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data file is simple. One day per line with the date in one column and the number of actions in the other column.  Here are the last few days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
 2013-02-14 | 24349
 2013-02-15 | 17396
 2013-02-16 | 12645
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Interactivepython</category><category>Python</category><category>Runestoneinteractive</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/02/we-passed-3-million-entries-in-our-log-data-for-interactivepython-org-which-got-.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Everyday Python - New Blog</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/01/everyday-python-new-blog.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've decided that it will be best to keep my personal blog separate from the new Everyday Python blog project.  All of the infrastructure to make the posts interactive just work so much better when I have control of the server and everything else.  So  You can head over to &lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/courselib/everyday"&gt;Everyday Python&lt;/a&gt; and click on the Everyday Python link there, or if you want to subscribe to the RSS feed for that project you can use &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/everydaypython"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/01/everyday-python-new-blog.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Generating a password - part 1</title><link>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/01/generating-a-password-part-1.html</link><dc:creator>Brad Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK, here is the first installment of the new Everyday Python series.  Today I'm just providing a link, as I still have some infrastructure work to get done in order to publish each installment both here and at Runestone Interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://interactivepython.org/courselib/static/everyday/2013/01/2_password.html"&gt;Generating a password part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Python</category><guid>http://reputablejournal.com/posts/2013/01/generating-a-password-part-1.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>