<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Jterm11 | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/categories/jterm11/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-09T11:55:46-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Road Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/26/the-long-road-home/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/26/the-long-road-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>4:00 PM Laguardia Airport</p>


<p>I have never wanted to be home so badly in all my life.  The group of 16 is sitting here in the American Eagle concourse of Laguardia.  We are at the airport very early for several reasons.  Number one, they are remodeling the lobby of the Seafarers and it sounded like the entire building was going to fall down.  Number two, the "seafarers" watching TV on the Mezzanine were on their second bottle of alcohol (gin for breakfast and whiskey for lunch) and were starting to creep everyone out.  Number three we though that this mornings snow might have traffic all backed up and we didn't want to be fretting our way through security, but as it turned out we got over here in no time at all.  Number five, we feared that there would be long lines at checkin and security due to flight changes and cancellations, which also proved to be a non-issue.  So, here we sit, two hours before boarding, the flight is on time so far...</p>


<p>The morning started out early, I was wide awake at 4AM, my mind on the trip home today.  We had to be out the door at 7AM to catch our train to Stamford Connecticut, where we visited NBC.  We had two great speakers today John Fritsche, and Bucky Gunt (Google him, he's won a ton of Emmys).  Unfortunately as we were on the train to Stamford some lovely white flakes of snow began to come out of the sky.  Sadly in New York even a few white flakes raise havoc with the schedules at Laguardia, Newark, and JFK.  On top of that tomorrow there is a winter storm watch out for our area.</p>


<p>Backing up to this morning again.  We got to the Union Square station where we were going to take any of the uptown bound trains to grand central station.  We told everyone, if the cars are crowded meet up on the platform  The cars were indeed crowded but after our london experience you would not believe how proficient our students have become at jamming themselves onto a subway.  So we all made it onto the train.  But not 30 seconds after we got off both Craig and I came up one student short.  I knew that student was on the train because I saw him and talked to him on the way to grand central.  But just like that he was gone!  Where did he go?  Did he fail to "mind the gap?"  Was he abducted by a band of roving gypsies?  Did a crazed herd of subway rats drag him away?  We had to move to the platform to catch our train to Stamford and unfortunately this student did not have his cell phone along.  So one stayed behind until the last possible minute to see if he returned, and the rest of us went on to catch our Stamford train.  Sadly, we had lost him.  Well, I knew that other than missing the NBC presentations he would be fine.  He could always go back to the hotel and meet us there later.</p>


<p>As we were standing in the snow in Stamford he finally called.  He was at a pay-phone and was safe and sound.  He had gone up the stairs following someone in a coat that looked suspiciously like Craig's.  After following not-craig for a while he finally realized that he was following the wrong guy.  By then he didn't know how to get back to us and we were probably gone by then anyway.  We are all hopeful that this will be the final mass transit mishap of the trip!  -- A short update craig just surmised that our inbound plane is 20 minutes ahead of schedule.  So, the good news is that we have an inbound plane, it is in the air, and it is ahead of schedule.  Yea!!</p>


<p>5:30  Well, scratch that... Our plane is actually now going to arrive about 16 minutes late.  It took off late from Charlotte, so is behind schedule.</p>


<p>9:23 CST:  Finally off the plane, after landing only about a minute late we were informed by the captain that an AA 737 landed just 10 seconds ahead of us.  Unfortunately they only have one ground crew so we wait on the tarmac unable to pull into our gate.  Finally we pull into the gate but we wait another 10 minutes before someone finally moves the jet bridge into place.  I'm pretty sure that was Cat having her final revenge on me for publicly calling her out in an earlier post.</p>


<p>But, all is well that ends well.  Even though we waited a long time (25 minutes) to get off the plane, our luggage was waiting for us at baggage claim, so there was no additional wait there.  By 10PM Craig and I were in my car, yes my car, freedom, no reliance on public transportation, no waiting for cranky gate agents, we could just get in my car and drive the last 2:20 minutes to get home to Decorah.  We arrived just after midnight.  Sweet.  It was a great trip, but there's no place like home.</p>


<p> </p>


<p> </p>


<p> </p>


<p> </p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-6608147763903952442?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Miss the Most After 21 Days on the Road]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/25/things-i-miss-the-most-after-21-days-on-the-road/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/25/things-i-miss-the-most-after-21-days-on-the-road</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><ol><li><strong>My Family</strong> -- This has been a great trip,and I think everyone has been getting along very nicely.  Its fun to watch a mixed group of students come together and form new friendships over the course of a couple of weeks.  At least one trip romance has blossomed.  But, I miss my wife, and I have missed way too many basketball games.  I keep watching the video of Josh's first varsity game over and over.</li><li><strong>My House</strong> -- We have had some pretty nice accommodations along the way, and a few sketchy ones as well.  Sadly, the last two days here in New York are the worst of the trip.  A couple of the students just told me that they slept with their winter coats on last night because their room was so cold!  My room was warm, and the sheets were clean but the whole place is pretty worn and grimy looking.  And, there is just one kind of gross shower for each half of our floor.  But the quiet!!  The week in London at the "Royal National"  was not very royal but again the sheets and rooms were clean and I had my own nice clean bathroom.  By far the best of the trip was the hostel in Interlaken.  But I am so looking forward to getting home to my own bed and my own shower, and my own hot water and tea...</li><li><strong>Cooking for myself</strong> -- Its been fun enjoying the local cuisines along the way.  Germany:  Schnitzel and Wurst and the beer at the Hofbrau house.  Switzerland: Interlaken more good german food but Lausanne was not so interesting.  Torino:  We had an awesome little meal at a neighborhood restaurant in Torino and some other good pasta options as well.  The challenge was finding restaurants that could accommodate all of us.  Most of them were pretty small so to fit the entire group we ended up using some cafeteria style places where everyone could work their way through.  London:  Good Indian, Chinese, and of course the fish and chips at the pubs was really good.  But, I'm ready to cook some of my favorites and just eat a little less!</li><li><strong>My Routine</strong> -- I'm such a creature of habit.  I miss getting up in the morning and doing Kettlebells, I miss getting up and just going up to my office to quietly read the news and have a cup of tea.  On the road I have to shower and get dressed before I can go find someplace to sit, and read, and even then it is not quiet, its someplace like starbucks or some local coffee joint that is bustling with activity.  I end up not reading and people watching.</li><li><strong>Playing 500</strong> -- Another great part of the rhythm of my life at home is gathering on the weekends to play cards with friends.  Around the table we catch up, discuss Decorah and National politics, parenting, and whatever.  Some nights are really intense, and some nights can be downright depressing if the cards are bad.  But nobody really remembers who won or lost a week later.</li><li><strong>Decorah</strong> -- Three weeks of being in big cities really reminds me of all the things I appreciate about our community.  I love going into a restaurant and knowing the staff, and knowing that while I eat my lunch I'm going to see people I know and have the chance to catch up with them.  I miss having my coffee at Java Johns were again I know the staff, and all of the interesting people that come in each morning.  I miss the smallness and familiarity.</li></ol></div>


<div></div>


<div></div>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-4352687159455891480?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[30 Rock]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/25/30-rock/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/25/30-rock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So today Craig and I had an afternoon to do some site seeing.  Despite the cold cold temperatures here in new york we decided to start with some Dim Sum.  So, we headed to Chinatown.  I took out the trusty Urbanspoon app on my phone and we were soon headed to Ping's.  Good Dim Sum at a great price.  Great shrimp and pork dumplings, Great potstickers and fried spring rolls.  The beef short ribs were OK, but not my favorite.  We finished up with some fried bacon wrapped shrimp.  A great way to close out the meal.  We were stuffed and only a few bucks poorer.</p>


<p>After lunch we headed up to 30 rock to do the studio tour and visit Top of Rock.  The studio tour was fun.  We saw Dr. Oz's studio (who??) and the Jimmy Fallon set, also home to Johnny Carson's show when he was in New York.  Finally we saw the SNL set.  Lots of great memorabilia and great memories in looking at that set.  Unfortunately there is a no picture policy on the tour so nothing to share there.</p>


<p>What I can share is this video clip.  Partway through the tour, our guides asked for a couple of volunteers to 'do some reading'  Craig and I both volunteered, and it turned out they were going to show us how a mini news broadcast goes together.  So, Craig is the anchorman, and I am the weather guy.  Its not as easy as it looks standing in front of the green screen, reading the teleprompter, and moving pointing at something nonexistent behind you.</p>


<object type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="400" height="225" data="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000"><param name="flashvars" value="intl_lang=en-us&photo_secret=d8e0373a91&photo_id=5402162164"></param><param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377"></param><param name="bgcolor" value="#000000"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377" bgcolor="#000000" allowfullscreen="true" flashvars="intl_lang=en-us&photo_secret=d8e0373a91&photo_id=5402162164" height="225" width="400"></embed></object>


<p>Sadly Flickr uses flash to do these embedded videos, Here's a link to the mov non flash file I uploaded... http://www.flickr.com/photos/bonelake/5402162164/</p>


<p>After the tour we went up to the Top of Rock experience.  This is a great view of the city on a nice mostly clear day.  Here's a few photos for you to enjoy the view from up there as well.  We had hoped to close out the afternoon with a happy hour cocktail at the Rainbow Room, but it was closed.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2331.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TT9QQBlBJpI/AAAAAAAAALg/gVNYzxouN-I/IMG_2331.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2331.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></p>


<p><img title="IMG_2336.jpg" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TT9QR4SNgxI/AAAAAAAAALk/TwVRQp8mOyE/IMG_2336.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2336.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></p>


<p> </p>


<p><img title="IMG_2339.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TT9QTvmnxeI/AAAAAAAAALo/AwgkekoHeXA/IMG_2339.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2339.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-5202653552439122819?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jet Lag Recovery Mode]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/24/jet-lag-recovery-mode/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/24/jet-lag-recovery-mode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm sitting in Starbucks off Union Square, its 6:30 here in Manhattan and I'm wide awake.  I made it until about 9:30 last night but then fell soundly asleep until 2:30AM, 8:30AM London time of course.  The relative quiet of my room at Seafarers International house was awesome.</p>


<p>The flight home was a Godsend as well.  I went up to the desk to ask if I could change from a center to an aisle seat.  The lady said no problem, she moved me to row 31 and said that it was likely nobody else would be beside me.  So yes, I had a whole row to myself for the flight home.  As it turned out we all could have had our own rows as the back third of the plane was pretty much empty.</p>


<p>Following all instructions we arrived at Heathrow three hours in advance of our flight, the Picadilly line was much more crowded that we expected it to be for 7:30 on a sunday morning.  But when we got to heathrow, there was no waiting at the continental desk to check in for our flight, and there was virtually no waiting in the security line either.  So, we had plenty of time to sit around the gate area and wait for our flight.  I think we all spent more time waiting to get through passport control at Newark than we did in the security line at Heathrow.</p>


<p>We just missed the 3:15 train to New York Penn Station, so we ended up having to wait there for the 4:04.  Every other hour of the day has an xx:28 train to Penn station except for 3pm.  Once we got into the city we had to get subway passes for everyone.  Unlike London, it is impossible in New York to use a credit card to by 26 unlimited passes.  So, we had to trudge to the Herald Square station and have everyone line up to use their own cards to get their subway passes for the two days here in New York.</p>


<p>Finally, about 4 hours after landing we made it to Seafarers.  It is midnight London time, but everyone was excited to eat some american food, and catch the end of the Packers, Bears game.  More american football was to come with the Steelers and the Jets.  Craig and I went to watch the end of the Packers game at TGI Fridays, and then headed out to Pete's Tavern.  It was great to have an American hamburger, with blue cheese!  I loved the fish and chips at all of the london pubs, but it was really nice to be back home.  Although we are still a 3 hour flight from Minneapolis I feel like we are close enough to home to reach out and touch it.</p>


<p>Today we have a group  meeting at 9, then a speaker from NBC Olympics at 10.  Everyone is on their own for the day after our speaker, until we have our final group dinner tonight.  Tomorrow will be a busy day as we have a meeting in Connecticut, and then by mid afternoon the group will begin to disperse for the various flights back home.</p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-5030927952139964923?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Premier League]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/22/premier-league/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2011/01/22/premier-league</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img title="IMG_2316.jpg" src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TTs3v8onh4I/AAAAAAAAALU/FtE05itJakg/IMG_2316.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2316.jpg" width="200" height="150" /></p>


<p>I can't think of a better way to end a trip to London that with a Premier League Football match.  We were very fortunate to get group tickets to the Fulham versus Stoke City match this afternoon.  Fulham plays in a venue known as Craven Cottage.  Its a smaller, more intimate stadium, but we ended up with great seats.  We were in about the 24th row behind and to the keepers left of the goal.  A high hard kick over the crossbar would land right in my lap.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2324.jpg" src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TTs3tsRgiTI/AAAAAAAAALQ/Vp1f1ONprCY/IMG_2324.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2324.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></p>


<p>Fulham won the game handily 2 nil with Clint Dempsey scoring both goals for Fulham.  We thought, briefly, about a USA USA chant for Dempsey, but decided that might not be appreciated by all of the other football fans around us, so we just cheered loudly.</p>


<p>Going to an English Premier League match is a fun experience. We sat in the neutral zone of the stadium so we were not right in with the Fulham or the Stokes City fans.  So our section was a bit quieter than all the others.  We were the closest to the Stokes City visitors section and it was really a riot to listen to them sing, and chant, and carry on throughout the game.  They only quieted down about midway through the second half when it became very clear that there was no way they were going to win the game.</p>


<p>There were a couple of Dads right behind me that had brought their two young boys to the game, so it was interesting to listen to them explain football to the boys, who already knew as much about the game as many of us.  It was a great experience and one that I will remember fondly for a long time.</p>


<p>The last few days are really a blur.  We have had more great meetings and class discussions, and finally some time to explore the city on our own.  Quite honestly I'm 'museumed out' at the moment.  I've been to The British Museum, The London Transportation Museum, the Tate Modern, The London Docklands, The Imperial War Museum, and the British Library.  All were interesting in their own way, but you get museum, and information overload at some point.</p>


<p>A couple of the highlights for me were the Transportation Museum, seeing the development of the London Underground, beginning in the 1830s and moving forward is a pretty interesting study in engineering, and city planning.   The development of tunneling technologies, and the escalator were really interesting.</p>


<p>Another highlight was seeing a letter from Ada Lovelace to Charles Babbage at the British Library.  The library has labelled this letter as the first computer program, as she is explaining how to program the difference engine to solve a mathematical problem that had never been solved by hand before.  Also at the Library was Handel's original score for the Messiah!  You could see his notes as well as the names of the soloists that were performing the different parts.  They also have one of four copies of the Magna Carta on display.  This is a document written in 1215 or so, and is widely considered to be a model for our own constitution.</p>


<p>Last night we had our final group dinner in London, and the Imperial China restaurant.  We had our own room, with a Karaoke machine and a special menu.  Tons of food, and great fun was had singing karaoke by all.    Here you can see Paul, Joe, and Carl treating us to a country song.  We also had Rap, Glen Campbell, and even a couple of Disco numbers.  It is really strange to think that all of these students know the lyrics to every Backstreet boys song ever written.</p>


<p><img title="IMG_2305.jpg" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_wISL1SSAaEA/TTs3zOSV8BI/AAAAAAAAALY/3W0K3rSBHeQ/IMG_2305.jpg?imgmax=800" border="0" alt="IMG_2305.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></p>


<p>Tomorrow is an early morning as we have to be on the Tube going to heathrow by 7:30.  We leave London at around 11:15am and arrive in New York at about 3:00pm.  We've all enjoyed our time in Europe, but we are also ready to be back in the states again.  I know that even after a proper football game this afternoon, a number of the students are hoping to make it</p>


<p> </p>


<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2759017781463016019-3432422924557260243?l=blog.bonelakesoftware.com' alt='' /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
