<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Namibia | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/categories/namibia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-09T13:19:13-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saying Goodbye to Namibia]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/07/06/saying-goodbye-to-namibia/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/07/06/saying-goodbye-to-namibia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sitting in the lobby of the Hotel Safari this morning.  We've checked out and are just hanging here until about 11:00 before we head to the airport.  It seems like a lifetime ago that we checked in here, exhausted, and grubby after 39 hours of travel from the USA.  Now we are refreshed, our bodies are on the right time zone and heading on to the next segment of our journey.  Its really strange to think that I'm heading to Israel, while the rest of the group is heading to cape town.  One consolation is that I'll be enjoying nice warm 90 degree weather, while they will be in Cape Town's winter at 59 degrees.</p>


<p>Last night we had a very nice dinner at Nampa and Matty's house.  I'm very jealous of Matty's indoor wood fired oven.  He had obviously been grilling meat for us all afternoon.  Not only does it make delicious meat but it also heats their family room.  It was amazing to hear the story of these two Luther College Alums.  They were at Luther in the mid 90's, but by the time they found their way to college in the USA they were married and had small children.  They are so grateful to the people of Decorah for their hospitality and help that they are always eager to open their home to Americans who are traveling in Namibia.  We worked hard on their youngest daughter to convince her that she must come to Luther to go to college.</p>


<p>As I think about the two purposes of our trip, the philanthropic, and the cultural I am inspired to try to return someday, and to help to keep up the good work that <a href="http://empoweringlearnersnamibia.blogspot.com">EmpoweringLearnersNamibia</a> has started.  There is so much more we can do to help, and it really doesn't take much money to accomplish a lot here.  For example a new Kindergarden school could be built to replace the 10x12 metal shack for about  $5000.00 US.  </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost Back to Windhoek]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/07/02/almost-back-to-windhoek/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/07/02/almost-back-to-windhoek</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, here we are on the B2 not 55km from Windhoek and the Safari Hotel.  Suddenly our coach makes a very bad noise and we begin to coast down the road.  Joey looks rather concerned.  We coast to a stop and pull over to the side of the road.  One of the few places in all of Namibia where there is almost no shoulder.  The diagnosis is dire, the clutch plate is out.  Luckily its only 1:15 in the afternoon and we are close to our destination.  David is on the phone getting another coach on its way.  This bus that we've spent so many hours with is not taking us any further.</p>


<p>So far we are all in good spirits.  The sun is out, the weather is nice.  We are joking about our plight and assessing our provisions.  In the cooler we have some apples, a half bottle of Riesling and one Windhoek light.  Suddenly Joey says… "I need a beer!"  We all crack up, we'd be happy to give Joey our last beer, he's been such a good sport with great humor this entire trip.</p>


<p>We are thankful that this little mishap happened here.  When we think of all the places this could have happened. The middle of Etosha, the middle of the desert, Each of which would be hours and hours from anywhere likely to have the ability to come and get us.  We'll be just fine, and this answers the important question of what to write about in today's blog.</p>


<p>UPDATE:  We're moving again, in a lovely, highly air conditioned coach.  Its just 2:55 so we were only delayed about 1:45.  When the replacement bus got here we formed a bucket brigade and transferred the luggage from one to the other in no time.  We're looking forward to arriving at the Safari and we'll still have some time to relax and refresh before we go to our dinner at Nampa and Matty's house.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photo Highlights From Namibia]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/photo-highlights-from-namibia/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/photo-highlights-from-namibia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, its really hard to pick out the photo highlights from this trip, but I decided to take a quick stab at it during my hour at the internet cafe today.  So, here's a link to the flickr photoset.  Hope you like it.</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Road Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/on-the-road-again/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/on-the-road-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aaaah relief!   After 3 days with absolutely no internet access we made a stop at an internet cafe this morning, where we all took to the internet like people who'd been deprived of water for three days.  Amazingly there was very little of importance in my inbox, so I guess all is well with the world.  I'm writing this on the bus as we make our six hour drive from the Etosha Safari Lodge down to Swakopmund.  Today we'll travel through both hill country and then through the Namib desert down to the coastal town of Swakopmud where we'll stay at the ELCRN guest house.  Swakopmund has been described as a slightly larger version of New Ulm Minnesota for those of you from Minnesota.</p>


<p>Yesterday was another amazing day.  We got up fairly early to observe a few animals at the Moringa water hole at the Halali Rest Camp, but it was a pretty quiet morning.  A few zebras, some Kudu, and a bunch of Guinea Hens.  We had some breakfast, and then set out for the day.  We had to be out of the park by 5:30PM (sundown) and we had a lot of animal viewing in store.</p>


<p>There were two real highlights of the day.  First, we witnessed a herd of 42 yes 42 elephants!  This herd included elephants of all ages, including babies up to the old bull that was clearly in charge of it all.  We saw to older males challenging each other for something, and younger males emulating them.  Its interesting to see them face off, then wrap their trunks together and then go head to head pushing on each other.  Just think of the strength behind all that pushing.  We even heard the old male trumpet to get everyone's attention and get the herd moving again.  At one point they must have smelled a lion or a leopard because everyone started running.  This didn't last very long and soon they were back to drinking at the water hole.  This must have been a unique gathering because even the Namibian's who were working on building a solar water pump were taking a break to watch all of this action.</p>


<p>We saw this same behavior with a  huge herd of Springbok and a dazzle of Zebra earlier in the day.  They were just standing around doing whatever springbok and Zebras do, when all of the sudden they all took off, David said this is because they smell a leopard.  After running a ways they stopped and stood very still, all of them just staring in one direction.  We tried to see what they were looking at but couldn't see anything but grass and bushes.</p>


<p>The second highlight of the day came at the end of the day when we saw Lions again.  Its amazing we saw them at all, they blend into the grass so well.  On one side of the road were four mature lions just sunning themselves, literally lying on their backs legs spread apart, soaking up the sun. Finally one of them got up and moved to a new spot so we were able to get a really good look.  On the other side of the road was a Lioness and her cubs, at first all we spotted were the ears sticking up next to one of the bushes, but with patience we were finally rewarded with some nice views of all the cubs and the mother.</p>


<p>A lot of what we saw today was the same animals that we have been seeing since entering the park, and after a while you just get numb to the whole thing until you remind yourself what a rare opportunity it is to see these animals in their natural habitat.  Animal Kingdom this is not.  One of the new animals we did see today was the heartbeats, another antelope that is the second fastest.  It gets its name from its horns which look like a heart when you see them from the front.</p>


<p>Its really crazy that we have just two days in Swakopmund and then on Sunday we head back to Windhoek in preparation for leaving Namibia on Monday. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Church]]></title>
    <link href="http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/church/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://bnmnetp.github.io/blog/2012/06/30/church</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Pastor Chad,</p>


<p>I'm writing today to let you know that I won't be in church for a while, probably about a year.  Believe me when I say that it is not your fault or the fault of anyone at First Lutheran.  Its just that I attended an ordination service for the Evangelical Lutheran Church In Namibia (ELCIN) here in Namibia, at the brand new church in the  Onesi parish.  This church just opened in April of this year so it was a great honor for them to host the ordination.  It is a large, but simple church built of bricks with a metal corrugated roof.  Its laid out in a traditional cross shape.    I have a number of points to share with you but I'll get right to the main reason for my absence…  The service lasted from 9AM until 4PM, yes SEVEN hours of church without a single break.  In my humble opinion I've now earned more than a few weeks off.</p>


<p>The bulletin we got when we arrived had a schedule on it.  The Ordination service started at 9:00AM right on time, it was to be done by 10:30 when the newly ordained would lead a full worship service.  At 12:00 we were to receive the greetings.  In reality, the worship service started at 12:30 and the greetings section started about 2:30.  Things last as long as they last here in Africa.  As you can guess, nobody would have any problem with the service going a little over an hour.</p>


<p>During the seven hours I was sitting on a plastic chair I had some time to reflect on what we might learn from the Namibians, and I'd like to take this opportunity to share them with you.</p>


<p>I'll start with Hospitality.  You need to know that the church was overflowing with people from all over the country, and indeed the world.  The bishop from  neighboring Angola and representatives from the government, local tribal leaders, and the governor of this part of the country.  There appears to be very strong cooperation between the church and state in this country.  There were probably 2,000 people in attendance, and many of them had to be seated outside.  </p>


<p>We arrived on our bus about 10 minutes before the service started, after driving three hours, including the last 28 kilometers on dirt roads.  We  were far from the the last ones there as we passed an amazing number of people walking to the service.  Many of them walked many miles, others were packed into the back of pickup trucks like sardines.  However, when we arrived we were ushered right over to an empty pew, reserved just for our group.  Unfortunately we did not all fit in our allotted pew, so Ethan and I were shown to the back row of the section reserved for pastors.  When the pastors processed in it was very clear that they needed our spots desperately, so we tried to move, but they wouldn't have anything to do with that!  Eventually plastic chairs were brought in and we were moved so that we could sit closer to our group.  Now here's an example of the kind of hospitality we should all aspire to, within a few minutes all of us were shuffled yet again, but this time we had pastors in our midst that served as translators for us for the entire service!  Some had their own personal translator while others were in pairs.  These pastors graciously shared their Oshiovambo hymnals with us, so that we could do our best to sing along on the SEVEN hymns on the hymn board.  And those seven were just a start, there were many many more that were sung as impromptu additions to the service. Amazingly, almost all of the hymn tunes were very familiar, so we could just about sing along in english using the words we remembered.</p>


<p>A note about the ELCIN and their need for pastors.  There is a great need for pastors here in Namibia, we were told that the ELCIN needs 40 pastors, which means that many congregations must make do with lay leadership only.  Today there were 5 candidates for ordination, but lest you think that each year they ordain five new pastors, we learned that they only do an ordination service every four years.  So for the candidates and the parishes this was a huge celebration.</p>


<p>We were treated as honored and distinguished guests the entire day.  During the greetings section of the service (which lasted an hour and a half)  our group was invited to come to the front and share a song.  So, we sang our Yalo song -- in  Oshiovambo --  and we were rock stars!  Of course we were already something of an oddity since other than three Finnish missionaries, we were the only white people in attendance.  After the service we were invited to dine with the presiding bishop to celebrate the occasion.  We were definitely in Lutheran hands as the dinner accommodations included carrot raisin salad, macaroni, and potato salad.   In a true namibian twist the meat section of the buffet featured grilled intestines along with several other options more appealing to the midwestern pallet.</p>


<p>Now let me turn to the Youth program.  While Adrian does an exceptional job, someone here in Namibia has really got this figured out.  In the crowd of people at this service were kids of all ages, and they stayed the entire time!  Many of the young kids sat on the floor near the front the entire service.  In addition, since the church was overflowing we saw 20-30 teen aged youth who stood outside the church putting their heads in the windows.  Yep, they stood in the windows for the entire service.  What an amazing thing.  Many of the parishes brought their youth choirs who were allowed to sing one and only one song during the collection of the offering.  They were awesome.  After the service there was a sort of impromptu battle of the choirs as they stood outside trying to out-sing each other.</p>


<p>Now here is what we might learn about stewardship from these great people.  Before the offering was taken an announcement was made.  First of all they were a bit short the previous week, so all were admonished to give generously.  She made the point that paper donations were definitely preferred over coins.  When the offering started, the choirs kicked in.  But now everyone was ushered to the front where a large basket was placed on a  chair, people came forward and placed their donations in the basket one by one.  Ethan told us that in other services he'd attended the offering might be taken up to three times, so you should plan ahead and divide your offering in thirds.</p>


<p>In terms of staffing I might say that having a master of ceremonies is an interesting idea.  A very distinguished older lady, Meme, in the native language, was in charge of first, letting everyone know how the service would unfold, and what to do when.  Again this is a nice way to help visitors feel at home and know whats coming up.  She did tend to ramble on and on a bit, as even our translators rolled their eyes after a while.  But her heart was clearly in the right place.  So the lesson here is that if we go this direction, we should choose this position with care.</p>


<p>Finally, I need to apologize to you.  In the ELCIN pastors are not called, they are sent, and in some cases the pastor is the first the congregation has ever had.  Nevertheless, I don't feel that you received  a proper welcome at First Lutheran.  After the pastors were ordained the secretary general formally announced where they were sent.  When the parish name was called the people of the parish stood and cheered, and clapped.   The women Ulilated and waved zebra tails in the air.  If that doesn't make a guy feel welcome I don't know what would.</p>


<p>Well, its about time to pack up the bus and head into Etosha national park.  You know I was just kidding about skipping for a year right?</p>


<p>Take care, and see you soon.</p>


<p>Brad</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
