<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: namibia | A Reputable Journal]]></title>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/categories/namibia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-01T15:14:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://reputablejournal.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Miller]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saying goodbye to Namibia]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/07/06/saying-goodbye-to-namibia/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/07/06/saying-goodbye-to-namibia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sitting in the lobby of the Hotel Safari this morning.  We've checked out and are just hanging here until about 11:00 before we head to the airport.  It seems like a lifetime ago that we checked in here, exhausted, and grubby after 39 hours of travel from the USA.  Now we are refreshed, our bodies are on the right time zone and heading on to the next segment of our journey.  Its really strange to think that I'm heading to Israel, while the rest of the group is heading to cape town.  One consolation is that I'll be enjoying nice warm 90 degree weather, while they will be in Cape Town's winter at 59 degrees.</p>


<p>Last night we had a very nice dinner at Nampa and Matty's house.  I'm very jealous of Matty's indoor wood fired oven.  He had obviously been grilling meat for us all afternoon.  Not only does it make delicious meat but it also heats their family room.  It was amazing to hear the story of these two Luther College Alums.  They were at Luther in the mid 90's, but by the time they found their way to college in the USA they were married and had small children.  They are so grateful to the people of Decorah for their hospitality and help that they are always eager to open their home to Americans who are traveling in Namibia.  We worked hard on their youngest daughter to convince her that she must come to Luther to go to college.</p>


<p>As I think about the two purposes of our trip, the philanthropic, and the cultural I am inspired to try to return someday, and to help to keep up the good work that <a href="http://empoweringlearnersnamibia.blogspot.com">EmpoweringLearnersNamibia</a> has started.  There is so much more we can do to help, and it really doesn't take much money to accomplish a lot here.  For example a new Kindergarden school could be built to replace the 10x12 metal shack for about  $5000.00 US.  </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost back to Windhoek]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/07/02/almost-back-to-windhoek/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/07/02/almost-back-to-windhoek</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, here we are on the B2 not 55km from Windhoek and the Safari Hotel.  Suddenly our coach makes a very bad noise and we begin to coast down the road.  Joey looks rather concerned.  We coast to a stop and pull over to the side of the road.  One of the few places in all of Namibia where there is almost no shoulder.  The diagnosis is dire, the clutch plate is out.  Luckily its only 1:15 in the afternoon and we are close to our destination.  David is on the phone getting another coach on its way.  This bus that we've spent so many hours with is not taking us any further.</p>


<p>So far we are all in good spirits.  The sun is out, the weather is nice.  We are joking about our plight and assessing our provisions.  In the cooler we have some apples, a half bottle of Riesling and one Windhoek light.  Suddenly Joey says… "I need a beer!"  We all crack up, we'd be happy to give Joey our last beer, he's been such a good sport with great humor this entire trip.</p>


<p>We are thankful that this little mishap happened here.  When we think of all the places this could have happened. The middle of Etosha, the middle of the desert, Each of which would be hours and hours from anywhere likely to have the ability to come and get us.  We'll be just fine, and this answers the important question of what to write about in today's blog.</p>


<p>UPDATE:  We're moving again, in a lovely, highly air conditioned coach.  Its just 2:55 so we were only delayed about 1:45.  When the replacement bus got here we formed a bucket brigade and transferred the luggage from one to the other in no time.  We're looking forward to arriving at the Safari and we'll still have some time to relax and refresh before we go to our dinner at Nampa and Matty's house.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Living Desert Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/the-first-adventure-of-the-day-was-the-living-desert-tour-with-tommy-tommy-is-a-/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/the-first-adventure-of-the-day-was-the-living-desert-tour-with-tommy-tommy-is-a-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://reputablejournal.com/images/25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6fb7qTldF1r729pmo1_1280.png" /></p>

<p>The first adventure of the day was the Living Desert tour with Tommy.  Tommy is a fabulous guide, we laughed our way through the tour as this guy is just one great one-liner after another.   We saw lots of interesting desert wildlife, all of which lives in the sand.  The photo is of Ann with a desert lizard clipped to her ear.  </p>


<p>Along the way we also found an Chameleon, a sidewinder, a horned adder, and lots of different beetles.  You just can't believe the beauty of the sand dunes.  These are the largest in the world with some of them over 1000 feet tall.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photo Highlights from Namibia]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/photo-highlights-from-namibia/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/photo-highlights-from-namibia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, its really hard to pick out the photo highlights from this trip, but I decided to take a quick stab at it during my hour at the internet cafe today.  So, here's a link to the flickr photoset.  Hope you like it.</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the road again]]></title>
    <link href="http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/on-the-road-again/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://reputablejournal.com/blog/2012/06/30/on-the-road-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aaaah relief!   After 3 days with absolutely no internet access we made a stop at an internet cafe this morning, where we all took to the internet like people who'd been deprived of water for three days.  Amazingly there was very little of importance in my inbox, so I guess all is well with the world.  I'm writing this on the bus as we make our six hour drive from the Etosha Safari Lodge down to Swakopmund.  Today we'll travel through both hill country and then through the Namib desert down to the coastal town of Swakopmud where we'll stay at the ELCRN guest house.  Swakopmund has been described as a slightly larger version of New Ulm Minnesota for those of you from Minnesota.</p>


<p>Yesterday was another amazing day.  We got up fairly early to observe a few animals at the Moringa water hole at the Halali Rest Camp, but it was a pretty quiet morning.  A few zebras, some Kudu, and a bunch of Guinea Hens.  We had some breakfast, and then set out for the day.  We had to be out of the park by 5:30PM (sundown) and we had a lot of animal viewing in store.</p>


<p>There were two real highlights of the day.  First, we witnessed a herd of 42 yes 42 elephants!  This herd included elephants of all ages, including babies up to the old bull that was clearly in charge of it all.  We saw to older males challenging each other for something, and younger males emulating them.  Its interesting to see them face off, then wrap their trunks together and then go head to head pushing on each other.  Just think of the strength behind all that pushing.  We even heard the old male trumpet to get everyone's attention and get the herd moving again.  At one point they must have smelled a lion or a leopard because everyone started running.  This didn't last very long and soon they were back to drinking at the water hole.  This must have been a unique gathering because even the Namibian's who were working on building a solar water pump were taking a break to watch all of this action.</p>


<p>We saw this same behavior with a  huge herd of Springbok and a dazzle of Zebra earlier in the day.  They were just standing around doing whatever springbok and Zebras do, when all of the sudden they all took off, David said this is because they smell a leopard.  After running a ways they stopped and stood very still, all of them just staring in one direction.  We tried to see what they were looking at but couldn't see anything but grass and bushes.</p>


<p>The second highlight of the day came at the end of the day when we saw Lions again.  Its amazing we saw them at all, they blend into the grass so well.  On one side of the road were four mature lions just sunning themselves, literally lying on their backs legs spread apart, soaking up the sun. Finally one of them got up and moved to a new spot so we were able to get a really good look.  On the other side of the road was a Lioness and her cubs, at first all we spotted were the ears sticking up next to one of the bushes, but with patience we were finally rewarded with some nice views of all the cubs and the mother.</p>


<p>A lot of what we saw today was the same animals that we have been seeing since entering the park, and after a while you just get numb to the whole thing until you remind yourself what a rare opportunity it is to see these animals in their natural habitat.  Animal Kingdom this is not.  One of the new animals we did see today was the heartbeats, another antelope that is the second fastest.  It gets its name from its horns which look like a heart when you see them from the front.</p>


<p>Its really crazy that we have just two days in Swakopmund and then on Sunday we head back to Windhoek in preparation for leaving Namibia on Monday. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
